<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>A Look Back At 2014</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/12/31/year-in-review/</Url><Content>Advertisement 2014 was an amazing year in startup news. In fact, we wrote more than 13,000 articles here on TechCrunch. That’s why we are giving you a handy TL;DR guide to remind you of all the big news from the past year. Apple: We predict that large phones will be the next big thing. WhatsApp: Sorry, I can’t hear you over the sound of all the $$$$. Amazon: Remember that one time we built a phone? Facebook: Too many apps. Foursquare: As many apps as users. Snapchat: There are no repercussions for bad behavior. Uber: There are no repercussions for bad behavior. Google: It only took us 6 years to make Android look good. Aol: We’re still here. Samsung: The next big thing was last year. Related Videos Play Video The Valley Girl Show Moves To Television 5:44 Play Video Tactus Phorm Overlays Typing Keys On Small Screens Play Video Anki Drive Upgrades to Customizable Tracks More Related Videos Xiaomi: ⌘C, ⌘V Xiaomi Mi Pad and an iPad Mini Retina Ello: Yo. Secret: Hey! Come back! Can anybody hear me? Lenovo: Soon we’ll own you too. Motorola: Made in China. Fitbit: You’re fatter than you think. Sony: We’re still releasing ‘The Interview.’ Actually stop everything, we’re not releasing it. Actually we’re releasing it. Spotify: Taylor Swift looks like a tall alien anyway. John Oliver: This is how you win the Internet. BlackBerry: QWERTY FTW! (WAIT, HOW DO YOU DISABLE CAPS LOCK?) Reddit: Now the front page to the worst of the Internet. Dropbox: Trading your privacy for 1TB of storage. Beats Electronics: Beats by Tim Cook. Airbnb: Remember that one time we changed our company logo to a vagina? Oculus Rift: Now you can experience life without leaving your house. Nintendo: New Super Smash Brothers Plus XL U! Netflix: Hey, do you guys remember Blockbuster? HBO: Hey, do you guys remember Netflix? Comcast: We still don’t care about you. Time Warner: We actually fucking hate you. Microsoft: Actually thinking differently. HP: Your printer ink is still low. Yo: Yo. Featured Image: Shutterstock 0 SHARES 0 Share 0 Tweet 0 Share 0 0 0 0</Content></Article>