<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>A Mash Note To George Lucas’ Museum  Signed By M C  Hammer (And Tech Leaders  Too)</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/05/15/dear-george-lucas/</Url><Content>San Francisco and Chicago are currently squaring off to be the future home of the Lucas Cultural Arts Museum, which will house filmmaking legend George Lucas’ collection of over 500,000 pieces of movie memorabilia. In an effort to keep the force in San Francisco, advocacy group sf.citi (San Francisco Citizens Initiative for Technology and Innovation) will publish a full page ad in the SF Chronicle today, which also happens to be the day after Lucas’ 70th birthday. Chicago’s chances of scoring the museum increased when The Presidio Trust rejected Lucas’ favored location back in February nearly two years after a proposal was first submitted. The letter, which is copied below, is signed by Oakland native M.C. Hammer, as well as local activists and tech leaders (San Francisco mayor Ed Lee has also voiced his support for the museum and vowed to find a home for it by the end of this month). In it, they say that the Lucas Cultural Arts Museum will contribute to arts education in the city. The museum has said that it plans to engage children, families, and educators by “weaving together art and science curricula” in interactive exhibits. While Lucasfilm is based in San Francisco, the Windy City has the advantage of being the part-time home of Lucas and his new wife Mellody Hobson, the president of Ariel Investments and a Chicago native. Like Lee, Chicago mayor Rahm Emanuel is also actively campaigning for the museum to be located in his city. Dear George Lucas, We care about arts education for our young people and believe  the Lucas Cultural Arts Museum belongs in San Francisco. Its  programs are important to all our innovators, artists, educators, and residents from every diverse background. You have contributed a great deal to the cultural and economic prosperity of our region and we appreciate the importance of what this extraordinary collection and vital public programs would offer to our future generations. Brian Armstrong, Coinbase Tony &amp; Cori Bates, Skype Marc &amp; Lynne Benioff, Salesforce Aneel Bhusri, WORKDAY” Michael &amp; Xochi Birch Marc Blakeman, AT&amp;T Zack Bogue, Data Collective Tyler Bosmeny,  Clever Jim Breyer, Accel Partners Kimberly Bryant, blackgirlsCODE Frank Caufield, Kleiner Perkins Brian Chesky, Airbnb Ron Conway, SV Angel Chris Cox, Facebook John Donahoee, Bay Jack Dorsey, Square Caleb Elston, Delighted Peter Fenton, Benchmark Capital Pete Flint, Trulia Paul Graham, YCombinator Dan Greenberg, Sharethrough MC Hammer Heather Harde Kevin Hartz, Eventbrite Julia Hartz, Eventbrite Reed Hastings, Netflix Jared Heyman, CrowdMed Rosco Hill, Blend Labs Reid Hoffman, Greylock Partners Drew Houston, Dropbox Chad Hurley, CoFDR YOU TUBE Richard Kovacevich, Retired, Wells Fargo &amp; Co. John Lasseter, PIXAR Max Levchin, Affirm Jessica Livingston, YCombinator Matt Mahan, Causes.com Andrew Mason, Detour Marissa Mayer, Yahoo! Todd McKinnon, Okta Joe &amp; Jennifer Montana Sean Parker Laurene Powell Jobs, Emerson Collective Hosain Rahman, Jawbone David &amp; Jacquelline Sacks, Yammer Sheryl Sandberg, Facebook Steve Sarner, tagged Eric Schmidt, Google sf.citi Nikita Shamgunov, MemSQL Evan Sharp, Pinterest Carole Shorenstein, Hays Ram Shriram, Sherpalo Ventures Ben Silbermann, Pinterest Biz Stone, Jelly Jeremy  Stoppelman, Yelp Jarrett Streebin, EasyPost Nirav Tolia, Nextdoor David Wadhwani, Adobe Joseph Walla, Hellofax Jeff Weiner, Linkedin Carlos Whitt, Leo Josh Wilson, Tsumobi Kevin Yeaman, Dolby Image by CakeCentral member PopsandTops</Content></Article>