<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>A User’s Guide To Disrupt SF 2014</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/09/05/a-users-guide-to-disrupt-sf-2014/</Url><Content>Hard to believe that Disrupt SF is just around the corner! As always, TechCrunch has partnered with an amazing array of folks who promise to make your experience at the conference better than ever. Party with TechCrunch and New Relic: Join us on Monday for the Official After Party at Mighty, sponsored by our friends at New Relic. Custom Disruptor Awards, yes plural: This year, five sponsors are awarding prizes to startups of their choosing from the Battlefield and Startup Alley. Accenture Open Innovation will present the Best Enterprise Disruptor Award to the startup with the most potential to play with the big dogs and blow the Fortune 500 away. Adyen is offering an around-the-world ticket to the winner of the Adyen Tech Globe Challenge. Enter here and show how your technology can scale for global growth. Baidu will present the “Baidu AI Innovation Award” to the company with the most visionary and innovative implementation of artificial intelligence or Big Data. Johnnie Walker will give a VIP Johnnie Walker Experience to the winner of the Keep Walking Award, an award given to recognize individuals who demonstrate they will not be defined by what they’ve done, but rather by what lies ahead. Marketplace from American Public Media will award $49,000 in broadcast media and production to the winner of the Startup Alley Audience Choice Award. Startup Alley Crawl: For the first time, UPS CONNECT is hosting a happy hour reception in Startup Alley on Monday and Tuesday afternoon. Enjoy a drink on them and peruse the amazing startups there to exhibit. Startup Alley Perks: TechCrunch wants Startup Alley to get the best support possible while at Disrupt, so we’re continuing to offer free office hours, this year from Perkins Coie and Norwest Ventures. What does that mean? It means that Startup Alley and Battlefield companies at Disrupt are entitled to schedule 1:1 meetings with attorneys from Perkins Coie to get courtesy legal advice and investment feedback from Norwest Ventures. Also, Cushman Wakefield is taking SUA participants on a tour of startup spaces in San Francisco during Disrupt. Don’t forget to sign up! Official Hardware Alley Sponsor: Autodesk Manufacturing is pleased to sponsor our fun-filled Hardware Alley day again on Wednesday, September 10. Official Break Sponsor: We know you love your coffee so head over to the Salesforce booth to find your caffeine fix during the conference session breaks. Official Spirits Sponsor: Have we got a treat for you! Our friends at Johnnie Walker will be pouring from their booth at the conference and serving cocktails at our receptions in their capacity as Official Spirits Sponsor. Cheers! Official Chat Platform of Disrupt: Atlassian is offering 6 months of unlimited group chat, video chat and screen sharing for free to Startup Alley! They are also giving each attendee 6 months of free HipChat Plus. Register here using code TCDisrupt14. Official Hackathon Platform: ChallengePost is reprising its role at the Hackathon, providing the platform for our wiki. Thanks, y’all! Exclusive Hackathon Hosting Partner: For the second Hackathon in a row, the folks over at Digital Ocean have generously offered free hosting credits for our intrepid hackers. Can’t wait to see what gets built using them! Watch us on the web: If you’re an arm-chair Disruptor, thanks to Ustream you can watch the conference action from the TechCrunch homepage or the Disrupt SF event page. Registration: Eventbrite has long been a TechCrunch partner. If you purchased a ticket, you used Eventbrite. We love them and we think you will, too. If you haven’t purchased a ticket, please go do that now!</Content></Article>