<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>All You Need To Know About The NYTimes com Paywall</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2011/03/17/all-you-need-to-know-about-the-nytimes-com-paywall/</Url><Content>The New York Times has just put up more information about its much awaited paywall. The digital subscription model was initially announced in January 2010 as an effort to create a second revenue stream while still preserving the newspaper’s advertising business. As we heard earlier, the subscription plan allows for free access to a set amount of content across digital platforms. When the monthly reading limit is reached, users who are not already home delivery subscribers will be asked to become digital subscribers. The subscription model will be implemented in the United States and globally on March 28, 2011. In Canada, digital subscriptions will be launched today. For non-home delivery subscribers, the basic package – NYTimes.com plus Smartphone App – will start at $15 every four weeks. For tablet access, the subscription will cost $20. The NYTimes.com plus Smartphone App package is currently available for purchase only by users in Canada. Here are the details: All users of NYTimes.com are able to enjoy 20 articles at no charge each month (including slideshows, videos and other forms of content). Beyond 20 articles and for open access to the site, users will be asked to become digital subscribers. On The Times’s smartphone and tablet apps, the Top News section will remain free. To delve into other sections, users will be asked to become digital subscribers. The Times is offering three digital subscription packages that allow users to choose the devices on which they want to access Times content. NYTimes.com will be included as part of any subscription. Details and pricing for these plans is available at http://www.nytimes.com/access. Introductory offers will be available. All New York Times home delivery newspaper subscribers receive free, unlimited access to NYTimes.com and the full content on all of The Times’s applications. Readers who come to Times articles through links from search, blogs and social media will be able to access those individual articles, even if they have reached their reading limit. For some search engines, users will have a daily limit of free links to Times articles. The homepage at NYTimes.com and all section fronts will remain free to browse for all users at all times. In keeping with Apple’s new subscription service terms, The Times will make 1-click purchase available in the App Store by June 30 to ensure that readers can continue to access Times apps on Apple devices. Subscribers to the print edition of the International Herald Tribune, the global edition of The New York Times, will receive free, unlimited access to NYTimes.com.</Content></Article>