<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Allez  Alley  Come Be A Part Of The Disrupt Europe Startup Alley</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2013/08/23/allez-alley-come-be-a-part-of-the-disrupt-europe-startup-alley/</Url><Content>Disrupt Europe in Berlin — the first time our flagship conference is coming to this part of the world — is fast approaching. We’ve got some amazing speakers lined up (with announcements of more still to come); we’re furiously preparing the Battlefield. And we’re calling all corners of the startup world to be a part of the action by getting involved in the Startup Alley. For those of you who are not familiar with the Disrupt format, the Startup Alley is often and rightly called the beating heart of the event. It’s where you get to go up close to check out new companies, meet their founders, and use the opportunity to mingle with other attendees — enterpreneurs, engineers who are still buzzing from coding at the Hackathon, VCs, journalists, scouts from big companies and more. With people constantly on the move and chatting, the Alley is the perfect complement to the more hushed tones of the conference. What makes the Startup Alley especially dynamic is that every day sees a different mix of companies on the floor, and it’s a measure of how much of an attraction in itself it is when you hear about how often the speakers — world-class entrepreneurs and investors — and many attendees of the conference putting in some legwork to check it out. To get a sense of the look and feel of the Alley, check out these videos from one of the days at our most recent Disrupt event, in New York, or this video with clips from other Alleys past. We’d love you to be a part of it with us in Berlin, where Disrupt Europe will take place from October 26-29 (Hackathon on 26-27; Main Event on 28-29). For those interested in the Alley, the price is €1190 for the Startup Alley Exhibitor Package, which also includes 2 conference passes, 1 day to exhibit, and the chance to spend some time with whole lot of awesome, like-minded people. More info here. Our sponsors help make Disrupt happen. If you are interested in learning more about sponsorship opportunities, please contact our sponsorship team here sponsors@techcrunch.com.</Content></Article>