<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Amazon Announces New Fire Tablets  E-Ink Kindles And A Special Fire For Kids</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/09/17/amazon-announces-new-fire-tablets-e-ink-kindles-and-a-special-fire-for-kids/</Url><Content>Advertisement Amazon released six new devices today with an eye on shipping them before the holiday season. The collection, which ranges from a new e-ink tablet called the Voyage to an 8.9-inch tablet that is lighter than the iPad Air and features Fire OS 4.0, an OS based on KitKat, is designed for reading, work and play. There’s also a new Kindle for kids that includes a $25 case and free parental control software and apps. The new Kindle Fire HDs come in 6- and 7-inch configurations and are considerably thinner than the previous Fire versions. They have the same design – an angular rear panel – but they are thinner and more powerful. They have a quad-core processor and front- and rear-facing camera, and come in black, white, blue, red and yellow. The new Kindles Fires cost $99 for the 6-inch and $139 for the 7-inch model. The new HDX model is a $379 powerhouse with a 2.5GHz processor and a 339 ppi pixel density. It is Amazon’s flagship device and can be used with a new accessory called the Fire Keyboard, a $59 wireless keyboard that connects to the Fire and allows you to edit documents and scroll on screen. Finally on the tablet front there’s the Fire for Kids, a special package that includes a rubber case and a year-long subscription to FreeTime, a service that locks down the Kindle for kids and allows them to view video, games, apps and books. It costs $149 for the 6-inch model and $189 for the 7-inch. The best thing? It comes with a two-year warranty that any parent would love: You can return it for any reason during that time and get a new one. Junior can drop it, smash it, and run over it with a Big Wheel and they’ll still take it back. Fans of e-ink will enjoy the Voyage, a surprisingly thin and light e-ink device with a $199 price tag and improved screen resolution. The new device feels like a slab of metal with a black and white screen on the front. Two buttons on either side vibrate when pressed to simulate a physical button tap. The device also has a touchscreen and can last up to six weeks on one charge. The older Kindle has been updated, as well, adding touch to the $79 device. All of the new devices have improved integration with the recently acquired GoodReads service that allows you to share your reading status with friends. A new Word Wise feature adds definitions of difficult words to books, a boon for students and English learners. All of the new devices are available for pre-order and will ship in October just in time for Olde Father Bezos to climb down the chimney and into your bed. 0 SHARES 0 Share 0 Tweet 0 Share 0 0 0 0</Content></Article>