<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Announcing The Full Agenda For TechCrunch Disrupt SF 2014</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/08/28/announcing-the-full-agenda-for-techcrunch-disrupt-sf-2014/</Url><Content>Advertisement TechCrunch Disrupt hits San Francisco September 6-10 at its new home at Pier 48, and we’re excited to announce the full agenda. The event will span five days and feature industry titans, noted thought leaders and experienced entrepreneurs. General admission tickets are still available. Luminaries like Peter Thiel, Vinod Khosla and Laura Arrillaga-Andreessen will speak. Unicorn club members Brian Chesky, Elizabeth Holmes and Scott Dietzen will share their insights on making big waves in formerly stagnant industries. Legendary tech figure and Dallas Mavericks owner Mark Cuban will also join us onstage. And, of course, Salesforce.com’s Marc Benioff will sit down with Michael Arrington for their annual not to be missed conversation. Quicken Loans founder and Cleveland Cavaliers owner Dan Gilbert will share with us how he’s rebuilding Detroit through technology and startups. We’ll also hear from founders Max Levchin, Daphne Koller and Julia and Kevin Hartz. Ev Williams and Walter Isaacson will share their grand experiment in the brave new world of publishing. Sean Rad will swipe right with us and we’ll geek out about gaming and Twitch with Emmett Shear and Kevin Lin. Some exciting health startups will give us a chance to peek into the future of digital medicine, and Liam Casey will tell us what it takes to make hardware plans come to fruition. And there are a few more surprises to come! Disrupt SF will kick off with die-hard developers and designers participating in the Hackathon. The 24-hour event starts on Saturday, September 6, and runs through the night until the teams take the Disrupt stage on Sunday to present their creations. During the conference, Startup Alley and Hardware Alley will host hundreds of startups. Each day our exhibition hall transforms with new companies to explore. Have a hardware product? We have just a handful of spots left. Join us in the Hardware Alley on Wednesday, and email emma@techcrunch.com if you have any questions. And finally, Disrupt SF will conclude with one Startup Battlefield company being awarded the famed Disrupt Cup and the $50,000 prize. We also encourage students to be a part of Disrupt SF. There are 300 student tickets available, so be sure to grab yours quickly. Early-bird tickets are available until September 1 after which the price jumps $1,000. While free tickets for the Hackathon are “sold out,” free tickets to see the Hackathon presentations became available today. Grab them while you can. If you’re interested in future sponsorship opportunities, please contact our sponsorship team here. As always, we want to hear from you. Questions? Comments? Email us at tips@techcrunch.com. See you at Pier 48! Monday, September 8, 2014 9:00am – 9:05am Opening Remarks by TechCrunch 9:05am – 9:25am Fireside Chat with Travis Kalanick (Uber), Moderated by Michael Arrington 9:25am – 9:45am Founder Stories with Max Levchin (Affirm, HVF), Moderated by Alex Wilhelm 9:45am – 10:05am In Conversation with Mark Cuban (Dallas Mavericks), Moderated by Matt Burns 10:05am – 10:30am What To Fund: Omar Hamoui (Sequoia Capital), Aileen Lee (Cowboy Ventures), James Slavet (Greylock Partners), Danny Rimer (Index Ventures) Moderated by: Matthew Panzarino 10:30am – 10:50am Fireside Chat with Elizabeth Holmes (Theranos) Moderated by Jon Shieber 10:50pm – 11:00am Special Announcement 11:00am – 11:15am BREAK 11:15am – 11:25am In Conversation with Bill Ready (Braintree/Paypal) 11:25am – 11:45am Fireside Chat with Liam Casey (PCH International) Moderated by John Biggs 11:45am – 12:05pm Founder Stories with Emmett Shear and Kevin Lin (Twitch) Moderated by Kyle Russell 12:05pm – 12:30pm Fireside Chat with Ev Williams (Medium) and Walter Isaacson (Aspen Institute) Moderated by Matthew Panzarino 12:30pm – 1:40pm LUNCH 1:40pm – 2:00pm In Conversation with Bill Hambrecht (WR Hambrecht + Co) and Clayton Christensen (Harvard Business School) Moderated by Jon Shieber 2:00pm – 2:30pm Zero to One: Peter Thiel (Founders Fund) Moderated by Alexia Tsotsis Startup Battlefield with Jason Kincaid 2:30pm – 2:35pm How the Startup Battlefield Works 2:35pm – 3:35pm Startup Battlefield Session One – Automate Judges: Josh Felser (Freestyle), Brady Forrest (Highway1), Bindi Karia (Silicon Valley Bank), Stephen Messer (Collective[i]) 3:35pm – 3:45pm BREAK 3:45pm – 4:45pm Startup Battlefield Session Two – Accelerate Judges: Adam Cahan (Yahoo), Tony Conrad (True Ventures), Sarah Leary (Nextdoor), David Prager (The Assembly) 4:45pm – 5:00pm BREAK 5:00pm – 6:00pm Startup Battlefield Session Three – Activate Judges: Cyan Banister (Banister Capital), Cyril Ebersweiler (HAXLR8R), Ryan Sweeney (Accel Partners), David Tisch (Box Group) 5:00pm – 6:00pm Startup Alley Crawl hosted by UPS CONNECT 9:00pm – midnight After Party hosted by New Relic at Mighty 119 Utah Street (between Alameda St &amp; 15th St), San Francisco Tuesday, September 9, 2014 9:00am – 9:10am Opening Remarks by TechCrunch 9:10am – 9:30am Fireside Chat with Dan Gilbert (Detroit Venture Partners) Moderated by Matt Burns 9:30am – 9:50am Founder Stories with Julia and Kevin Hartz (Eventbrite) Moderated by Mike Butcher 9:50am – 10:15am San Francisco’s Tech Culture Clash Moderated by Kim-Mai Cutler 10:15am – 10:35am In Conversation with Scott Dietzen (Pure Storage) and Mike Speiser (Sutter Hill Ventures) Moderated by Ron Miller 10:35pm – 10:50am BREAK 10:50am – 11:00am Special Product Announcement 11:00am – 11:25am Fireside Chat with Marc Benioff (Salesforce.com) Moderated by: Michael Arrington 11:25am – 11:45am In Conversation with Laura Arrillaga-Andreessen (Laura Arrillaga-Andreessen Foundation) Moderated by: Alexia Tsotsis 11:45am – 12:10pm Fireside Chat with Vinod Khosla (Khosla Ventures) Moderated by: Michael Arrington 12:10pm – 12:30pm Founder Stories with Ryan Hoover (Product Hunt) Moderated by: Josh Constine 12:30pm – 2:00pm LUNCH 2:00pm – 2:25pm Fireside Chat with Brian Chesky (Airbnb) Moderated by Ryan Lawler Startup Battlefield with Jason Kincaid 2:25pm – 2:30pm How the Startup Battlefield Works 2:30pm – 3:30pm Startup Battlefield Session Four – Streamline Judges: Tracy Chou (Pinterest), Josh Elman (Greylock Partners), Markus Spiering (EyeEm), Hunter Walk (Homebrew) 3:30pm – 3:45pm BREAK 3:45pm – 4:45pm Startup Battlefield Session Five – Transform Judges: Robert Brunner (Ammunition), Jessica Livingston (Y Combinator), Matthew Prince (Cloudflare), Steven Sinofsky (Harvard Business School) 4:45pm – 5:00pm BREAK 5:00pm – 6:00pm Startup Battlefield Session Six – Extend Judges: Gina Bianchini (Mightybell),  Daniel Burka (Google Ventures), Neil Sequeira (General Catalyst), Tomasz Tunguz (Redpoint) 5:00pm – 6:00pm Startup Alley Crawl hosted by UPS CONNECT 9:00pm – midnight After Party at Public Works 161 Erie Street (at Mission St), San Francisco Wednesday, September 10, 2014 9:30am – 9:40am Opening Remarks by TechCrunch 9:40am – 10:00am In Conversation with Daphne Koller (Coursera) Moderated by Frederic Lardinois 10:00am – 10:20am Fireside Chat with Sean Rad (Tinder) Moderated by Jordan Crook 10:20am – 10:40am In Conversation with Shervin Pishevar and Scott Stanford (Sherpa Ventures/SherpaFoundry), Tina Sharkey (Sherpa Foundry) Moderated by Ryan Lawler 10:40am – 11:00am Game of Drones Moderated by Darrell Etherington 11:00am – 11:10am Special Product Announcement 11:10am – 11:20am BREAK 11:20am – 11:25am Hackathon Highlights with Jeffrey Bennett and Sam O’Keefe 11:25am – 11:45am Fireside Chat with Dave Morin (Path) Moderated by: Matthew Panzarino 11:45am – 12:10pm Digital Medicine is the New Rx: Matthew Cooper (Carmenta Bioscience), Peter Hames (Big Health), Glen Tullman (7wire Ventures) Moderated by Sarah Buhr 12:10pm – 12:35pm The Convenience Economy: Matt Salzberg (Blue Apron), Rob Spiro (Good Eggs), Tony Xu (DoorDash) Moderated by Anthony Ha 12:35pm – 2:00pm LUNCH 2:00pm – 2:25pm Fireside Chat with Gil Penchina (Fastly) and Naval Ravikant (AngelList) Moderated by Michael Arrington 2:25pm – 2:40pm Startup Battlefield Alumni 2:40pm – 2:45pm Passing the Disrupt Cup 2:45pm – 2:55pm BREAK Startup Battlefield with Jason Kincaid 2:55pm – 3:00pm How the Startup Battlefield Works 3:00pm – 5:00pm Startup Battlefield Finals Judges: Roelof Botha (Sequoia Capital), David Lee (SV Angel), John Lilly (Greylock Partners), Marissa Mayer (Yahoo), Keith Rabois (Khosla Ventures), Kevin Rose (North, Google Ventures) 5:00pm – 5:30pm Cocktail Reception hosted by Live Journal 5:30pm – 6:00pm Closing Awards Ceremony 9:00pm – midnight After Party at Mezzanine 444 Jessie Street (between Mint St &amp; 6th St), San Francisco 0 SHARES 0 Share 0 Tweet 0 Share 0 0 0 0</Content></Article>