<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Announcing The 2011 Crunchies Finalists And Tickets On Sale Now</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2012/01/05/2011-crunchies-finalist/</Url><Content>Update: Tickets are now sold out. Be sure to keep your eye out for ticket giveaways and for when we release our next batch of tickets. The nominations have been tabulated and the votes are in. Over 300,000 nominations were calculated across 20 categories. Along with our partners GigaOm and VentureBeat, we are very proud to announce the finalists for 2011’s best in technology. Voting begins now. For 2011, we’ve added some new categories. Best Location App, Best Cloud Services and Biggest Social Impact join the Crunchies ranks this year. You’ll also find Best Social App, the NYC-dominated category of Best Shopping App, Best New Startup and the year’s best VC’s and Angel Investors. Newcomers like TaskRabbit’s Leah Busque and Keith Rabois for his angel investments (Airbnb, LinkedIn, Yammer, Path, YouTube) made the list of finalists, as well as industry favorites such as Marc Andreessen, Jack Dorsey, Mark Pincus and Ron Conway. There are some pretty good match-ups this year. Google+ is up against Facebook Timeline for Best Social App, along with the New New Twitter, Instagram, and Path 2.0). The Kindle Fire is competing with the iPad 2 for Best New Device. And Pinterest, Turntable.fm, Nest, Fab, and Codecademy are all vying for Best New Startup (even though two of those were complete pivots). LinkedIn founder Reid Hoffman is up for Angel of the Year. His seed investment in Zynga is worth 160 times what he paid for it. But AngelList founders Naval Ravikant and Babak Nivi are also finalists in the category for helping to democratize angel investing, along with Conway, Rabois, Y Combinator’s Paul Graham, and Kevin Rose (who has a killer portfolio that includes Twitter, Foursquare, Zynga, and Square). Who will win? Everyone is eligible and encouraged to vote. The rules state that you may vote once per day, per award category, until voting closes on Sunday, January 29, 2012 at 11:59pm PST. There are 20 award categories open for voting, recognizing the top accomplishments across a variety of fields and roles. If you are one of the finalists, create a badge and get your community excited about this honor and get them to vote for you. Winners will be announced on January 31, live at the Crunchies. In addition to today’s announcement of the Finalists, we are happy to release our next batch of tickets through Eventbrite. The release begins now, so act fast and get them while you can. Here are your Finalists: Best Technology Achievement (2010 winner: Google Self Driving Cars) Lytro (Related posts) NFC (Related posts) OnLive (Related posts) Siri (Related posts) Tesla Flat Pack Battery (Related posts) Best Social Application (2010 winner: DailyBooth) Facebook Timeline (Related posts) Instagram (Related posts) Google+ (Related posts) The New New Twitter (Related posts) Path 2.0 (Related posts) Best Shopping Application (2010 winner: Groupon) Birchbox (Related posts) Fab (Related posts) Gilt Groupe (Related posts) Lot18 (Related posts) Warby Parker (Related posts) Best Mobile Application (2010 winner: Google Mobile Maps for Android) Evernote (Related posts) Flipboard (Related posts) Pandora (Related posts) Spotify (Related posts) Square (Related posts) TaskRabbit (Related posts) Best Location Application (New category for 2011) Airbnb (Related posts) Foursquare (Related posts) Grindr (Related posts) RunKeeper (Related posts) Uber (Related posts) Best Tablet Application (2010 winner: Flipboard) djay (Related posts) Eventbrite At the Door (Related posts) Fotopedia (Related posts) GarageBand (Related posts) Netflix (Related posts) StumbleUpon (Related posts) Best Design (2010 winner: gogobot) Gojee (Related posts) Orchestra (Related posts) Path 2.0 (Related posts) Pinterest (Related posts) Quora (Related posts) Best Bootstrapped Startup (2010 winner: addmired) Github (Related posts) Imgur (Related posts) Instapaper (Related posts) Onesheet (Related posts) Tap Tap Tap (Camera+) (Related posts) Best Cloud Service (New category for 2011) Asana (Related posts) Box (Related posts) CloudFlare (Related posts) Dropbox (Related posts) Okta (Related posts) Twilio (Related posts) Best International Startup (2010 winner: Viki) Badoo (Related posts) Klarna (Related posts) Peixe Urbano (Related posts) Rovio (Related posts) SoundCloud (Related posts) Wonga (Related posts) Best Clean Tech Startup (2010 winner: SolarCity) Alta Energy (Related posts) Array Power (Related posts) EcoATM (Related posts) EcoMotors (Related posts) Hara (Related posts) Best New Device (2010 winner: iPad) Galaxy Nexus (Related posts) iPad 2 (Related posts) iPhone 4S (Related posts) Kindle Fire (Related posts) Nest (Related posts) Best Time Sink (2010 winner: Cityville) Modern Warfare 3 (Related posts) Quora (Related posts) Skyrim (Related posts) Turntable.fm (Related posts) Words With Friends (Related posts) Biggest Social Impact (New category for 2011) Charity: Water (Related posts) Khan Academy (Related posts) Kickstarter (Related posts) Practice Fusion (Related posts) Twitter (Related posts) Angel of the Year (2010 winner: Paul Graham) Ron Conway (Related posts) Paul Graham (Related posts) Reid Hoffman (Related posts) Keith Rabois (Related posts) Naval Ravikant and Babak Nivi (AngelList) (Related posts for Naval) (Related posts for Babak) Kevin Rose (Related posts) VC of the Year (2010 winner: Yuri Milner) Marc Andreessen &amp; Ben Horowitz (Related posts for Marc) (Related posts for Ben) Matt Cohler (Related posts) Vinod Khosla (Related posts) Aileen Lee (Related posts) Yuri Milner (Related posts) David Sze (Related posts) Founder of the Year (2010 winner: Mark Pincus) Leah Busque (Task Rabbit) (Related posts) Brian Chesky (Airbnb) (Related posts) Jack Dorsey (Square, Twitter) (Related posts) Susan Feldman &amp; Ali Pincus (One Kings Lane) (Related posts for Susan) (Related posts for Ali) Drew Houston (Dropbox) (Related posts) CEO of the Year (2010 winner: Andrew Mason) Dick Costolo (Twitter) (Related posts) Daniel Ek (Spotify) (Related posts) Phil Libin (Evernote) (Related posts) Mark Pincus (Zynga) (Related posts) Jeff Weiner (LinkedIn) (Related posts) Best New Startup of 2011 (2010 winner: Quora) Codecademy (Related posts) Fab (Related posts) Nest (Related posts) Pinterest (Related posts) Turntable.fm (Related posts) Best Overall Startup of 2011 (2010 winner: Twitter) Dropbox (Related posts) Instagram (Related posts) Gilt Groupe (Related posts) Spotify (Related posts) Square (Related posts) Tumblr (Related posts) 5th Annual Crunchies Awards Tuesday, January 31, 2012 Louise M. Davies Symphony Hall 201 Van Ness Ave. San Francisco, CA 7:30pm – midnight – Awards Ceremony and After Party A night of celebration with festive attire. Our sponsors help make the Crunchies happen, if you are interested in learning more about sponsorship opportunities during the ceremony or after-party, please contact Jeanne Logozzo at jeanne@techcrunch.com. For press credentials, please fill out this request form and confirmations will be sent separately via email.</Content></Article>