<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Announcing The New Convenience Economy Disrupt Panel With Blue Apron’s Matt Salzberg  Good Eggs’ Rob Spiro  And DoorDash’s Tony Xu</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/08/22/announcing-the-new-convenience-economy-disrupt-panel-with-blue-aprons-matt-salzberg-good-eggs-rob-spiro-and-doordashs-tony-xu/</Url><Content>Convenience is one of those problems that almost any entrepreneur can tackle, whether you are running an expansive business like WunWun’s on-demand delivery for everything, or running a specifically tailored business like YourMechanic. But some entrepreneurs are looking at the problem of convenience and pairing it with universal needs. With that in mind, I’d like to introduce some of the incredible speakers joining us on stage at TechCrunch Disrupt SF for The New Convenience Economy panel: Matt Salzberg from Blue Apron, Rob Spiro from Good Eggs, and Tony Xu from DoorDash. Each one of these companies has made its own strides — Blue Apron was recently valued over $500 million; Good Eggs raised a hearty $7.5 million Series A from Sequoia; and DoorDash has taken off in the South Bay with nearly $20 million in funding. But it’s not just these folks that are making waves. Sprig raised $10 million, Spoonrocket just raised $11 million, Caviar raised $15 million, Postmates raised $16 million, and Munchery just raised an additional $28 million. The space is on fire, which is why we’re absolutely delighted to have Salzberg, Spiro and Xu join us on stage. These guys will be joining an already-impressive speaker list for Disrupt SF, which currently includes among many others, Laura Arrillaga-Andreessen, Marc Benioff and Vinod Khosla — best yet, we have a number of surprises yet to announce. There is still time to snag a Disrupt SF ticket at early bird pricing. After September, the price jumps by $1,000. If you’re interested in becoming a sponsor, reach out to our sponsorship team for more information.</Content></Article>