<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Announcing The 8th Annual Crunchies Awards</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/11/05/announcing-the-8th-annual-crunchies-awards/</Url><Content>It’s that time of year again. One of Thanksgiving and … nominations for the 8th Annual Crunchies Awards. Once again TechCrunch writers will step away from their keyboards to celebrate the best of technology. As in years past, the tech community will give awards to the best and brightest startups, founders, investors and thought leaders in our industry. There are 20 Crunchies categories in all, including Founder of the Year and Best New Startup. Nominations are now open. and they close on December 3rd at 11:59pm PST. The ceremony will take place on Thursday, February 5, 2015 at 7:30 p.m. at Davies Symphony Hall in San Francisco. Davies is an elegant venue that has hosted some of the greatest musical performances in history, and the Crunchies will return for its fourth time this year. Following the awards, the Davies will also provide a festive playground for this year’s after party. As always there will be a hosted bar, hors d’oeuvres, intriguing interactive entertainment and other fun surprises. And tech bloggers. General admission tickets are available now. Seating is limited, and the event tends to sell out quickly. Our sponsors help make the Crunchies happen; if you are interested in learning more about sponsorship opportunities for the ceremony or after party, please contact sponsors@techcrunch.com. For press credentials, please fill out this request form and confirmations will be sent via email. See you at the Davies! The 8th Annual Crunchies Awards Thursday, February 5, 2015 Louise M. Davies Symphony Hall 201 Van Ness Ave. San Francisco, CA 7:30pm – midnight – Awards Ceremony and After Party A night of celebration with festive attire. Tickets are available now. Nominations open: Wednesday, November 5th Nominations close: Wednesday, December 3rd at 11:59pm PST Finalists announced: early January List of Categories and most recent winners: Best Technology Achievement (2013: bitcoin) Best On-Demand Service (2013: Airbnb) Best E-Commerce Application (2013: Wanelo) Best Mobile Application (2013: Snapchat) Fastest Rising Startup (2013: Upworthy) Best Health Startup (2013: One Medical) Best Design (2013: Pencil by FiftyThree) Best Bootstrapped Startup (2013: Imgur) Best Enterprise Startup (2013: Zendesk) Best International Startup (2013: Waze) Best Education Startup (2013: Duolingo) Best Hardware Startup (2013: Oculus VR) Can’t Stop, Won’t Stop (2013: Candy Crush Saga) Biggest Social Impact (2013: Edward Snowden’s NSA Revelations) Angel of the Year (2013: Chris Sacca) VC of the Year (2013: Peter Fenton, Benchmark) Founder of the Year (2013: Arash Ferdowsi &amp; Drew Houston, Dropbox) CEO of the Year (2013: Dick Costolo, Twitter) Best New Startup of 2014 (2013: Tinder) Best Overall Startup of 2014 (2013: Kickstarter)</Content></Article>