<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Announcing The Agenda For TechCrunch Disrupt Europe In London</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/10/06/announcing-the-agenda-for-techcrunch-disrupt-in-london-2014/</Url><Content>TechCrunch Disrupt lands in London October 18 – 21, and we’re excited to announce the full agenda. The event will span four days and feature noted thought leaders, experienced entrepreneurs and some of tech’s most promising up-and-comers. There will be a hackathon, a hall full of innovative companies and, of course, Startup Battlefield where 15 startups will launch and compete for the renowned Disrupt Cup. Tickets are still available. Founders, including Michael Acton Smith, Michelle Zatlyn and Justin Kan, will speak alongside venture capitalists eager to fund European startups. Neelie Kroes will give one of her last interviews before she leaves her post as vice president of the European Commission. We’ll meet the Google Ventures EU team for their first interview as a team and learn how they plan to take Europe by storm. Docker founder Solomon Hykes will be joined by Benchmark Partner Peter Fenton, to share their thoughts about how to create one of tech’s most promising enterprise companies. And that’s just the beginning. Disrupt Europe will kick off with die-hard developers and designers participating in the Hackathon. The 24-hour event starts on Saturday, October 18, and runs through the night until the teams take the Disrupt stage on Sunday to present their creations. During the conference, Startup Alley and Hardware Alley will host hundreds of startups. Each day our exhibition hall transforms with new companies to explore. Have a hardware product? We have just a handful of spots left. Join us in the Hardware Alley on Tuesday, and email emma@techcrunch.com if you have any questions. And finally, Disrupt Europe will conclude with one Startup Battlefield company being awarded the famed Disrupt Cup and the £30,000 grand prize. We also encourage students to be a part of Disrupt. There are student tickets available, so be sure to grab yours quickly. Early-bird tickets are available until October 11. If you’re interested in future sponsorship opportunities, please contact our sponsorship team here. As always, we want to hear from you. Questions? Comments? Email us at tips@techcrunch.com.   Monday, October 20, 2014 9:00am – 9:05am Opening Remarks by TechCrunch 9:05am – 9:30am Fireside Chat with Google Ventures EU: Tom Hulme, Avid Larizadeh, Bill Maris, Peter Read, MG Siegler, Eze Vidra 9:30am – 9:50am In Conversation with Uri Levine (Waze, FeeX) 9:50am – 10:10am Fireside Chat with Maelle Gavet (Ozon) 10:10am – 10:30am Founders Stories: Onno Faber (TapTalk) 10:30am – 10:45am BREAK 10:45am – 11:10am From Shoreditch to Berlin and Beyond, Building the European Tech Hubs: Carlos Eduardo Espinal (Seedcamp) , Rohan Silva (Second Home), Tine Thygesen (Everplaces), Jason Whitmire (Earlybird) 11:10am – 11:35am Fireside Chat with Neelie Kroes (European Commission) 11:35am – 12:00pm The Acceleration of Digital Medicine: Peter Hames (Big Health), Dr. Dominic King (HELIX Centre, Imperial College London) 12:00pm – 12:25pm Fireside Chat with Justin Kan (Y Combinator) 12:25pm – 12:45pm Fireside Chat with Jason Goldberg (Fab, Hem) 12:45pm – 2:00pm LUNCH 2:00pm – 2:10pm Hackathon Highlights 2:10pm – 2:30pm Fireside Chat with Tim Armstrong (AOL) Startup Battlefield with Mike Butcher 2:30pm – 2:35pm How the Startup Battlefield Works 2:35pm – 3:35pm Startup Battlefield Session One – Access Judges: Niko Bonatsos (General Catalyst),  Jon Bradford (Techstars), Bindi Karia (Silicon Valley Bank), Brenden Mulligan (Cluster) 3:35pm – 3:45pm BREAK 3:45pm – 4:45pm Startup Battlefield Session Two – Explore Judges: Benjamin Joffe (HXLR8R), Nenad Marovac (DN Capital), Florian Meissner (EyeEm), Sitar Teli (Connect Ventures) 4:45pm – 4:55pm BREAK 4:55pm – 6:00pm Startup Battlefield Session Three – Track Judges: Alice Bentinck (Entrepreneur First), Simon Cook (DFJ Esprit), Alex Macpherson (Octopus Ventures), Christophe Maire (angel investor) 9:00pm – midnight After Party at The Gable 25 Moorgate, London EC2R 6AR   Tuesday, October 21, 2014 9:00am – 9:10am Opening Remarks by TechCrunch 9:10am – 9:40am Funding Europe’s Next Unicorn: Philippe Botteri (Accel Partners), Saul Klein (Index Ventures), Eileen Burbidge (Passion Capital), Daniel Waterhouse (Balderton Capital) 9:40am – 10:05am In Conversation with Brian Armstrong (Coinbase) 10:05am – 10:30am Founders Stories with Michael Acton Smith (Mind Candy) 10:30am – 10:40am Startup Battlefield Alumni Update 10:40pm – 11:00am BREAK 11:00am – 11:25am Fireside Chat with Matthew Prince and Michelle Zatlyn (Cloudflare) Startup Battlefield with Mike Butcher 11:25am – 11:30am How the Startup Battlefield Works 11:30am – 1:00pm Startup Battlefield Finals Judges: Mat Braddy (Just Eat), Sonali DeRycker (Accel), Brent Hoberman (PROfounders Capital), Klaus Hommels (Lakestar), Mattias Ljungman (Atomico) 1:00pm – 2:30pm LUNCH 2:30pm – 2:50pm In Conversation with Morten Lund (LundXY) 2:50pm – 3:10pm Founder Stories with Eben Upton (Raspberry Pi) 3:10pm – 3:30pm Fireside Chat with Eric Wahlforss (Soundcloud) 3:30pm – 3:50pm Fireside Chat with Mikkel Svane (Zendesk) 3:50pm – 4:05pm BREAK 4:05pm – 4:30pm Money, Money, Money: Taavet Hinrikus (Transferwise), Damian Kimmelman (DueDil), Jeff Lynn (Seedrs) 4:30pm – 4:50pm Founder Stories with Adora Cheung (Homejoy) 4:50pm – 5:10pm Fireside Chat with Ed Vaizey (Minister for Culture and the Digital Economy) 5:10pm – 5:35pm Fireside Chat with Peter Fenton (Benchmark) and Solomon Hykes (Docker) 5:35pm – 6:00pm Founder Stories with Frédéric Mazzella (BlaBlaCar) 6:00pm – 6:30pm Closing Awards Ceremony 6:30pm – 7:00pm Closing Cocktail Reception, hosted by Microsoft Ventures</Content></Article>