<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Arkady Dvorkovich  assistant to the President of Russia  to speak at TechCrunch Moscow</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2010/11/17/arkady-dvorkovich-assistant-to-the-president-of-russia-to-speak-at-techcrunch-moscow/</Url><Content>Well, we’ve landed a great addition to our speakers at TechCrunch Moscow. Arkady Dvorkovich is a Russian economist and assistant to the President of the Russian Federation 2008. A Chess master, he spends his days advising the President Medvedev on economic policy, but also it’s approach to technology innovation strategy. Dvorkovich is also no slouch as a blogger, with his own slot on The Huffington Post. Respect. For those of you that need to get up to speed on this event, on December 13, TechCrunch Europe is coming to Moscow, Russia, for our first ever “TechCrunch Moscow”. The event will be held at the first Russian private tech incubator, the Digital October Center, located in a historical manufacturing building Krasny Oktyabr (or “Red October” / Красный Октябрь in Russian). You can now buy tickets here. TechCrunch Moscow attendees will enjoy a full day packed with speeches by the leaders of the industry, networking opportunities and a chance to preview promising Russian tech startups. Co-organised by TechCrunch Europe together with Kite Ventures, the conference will focus on the key issues regarding tech entrepreneurship in Russia. As the programme is at full capacity, there are no longer any speaking slots so please do not ask the TechCrunch team for this. For all sponsorship and exhibitor inquiries, please get in touch with Events &amp; Sponsorship Director Alena [AT] TechCrunch.com. Please ensure all emails are in English. Thank you! More details on the final program will be announced, but for now we can say that Arkady Volozh, CEO of Yandex, Russia’s leading search engine; Annelies van Den Belt, CEO of SUP/Livejournal; Semyon Voinov, founder of Zeptolab and creator of “Cut the Rope”; Demyan Kudriavtsev, CEO of Kommersant; Lukasz Gadowski, founder of Team Europe Ventures; Oskar Hartmann, founder and CEO of KupiVip, and many others will be among the speakers.</Content></Article>