<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Burning Man Founders Admit The Festival Has Jumped The Shark But That’s Okay</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/08/28/burning-man-founders-admit-the-festival-has-jumped-the-shark-but-thats-okay/</Url><Content>The stories of billionaires flying into Burning Man on private jets with hired sherpas, body guards turning people away from VIP art cars and private glamp camps going for $25K in dues seems to be on everyone’s lips at the annual festival in the desert. While this is not the norm, it’s a reality and it has many asking if Burning Man has jumped the shark. A room full of bloggers, reporters and photographers from all over the world gathered together at the center of camp yesterday to ask Burning Man main co-founder Larry Harvey and Black Rock City manager Harley Dubois that very question. Burning Man has jumped the shark, at least in the sense that it is now much different than the way it started and how it’s perceived, according to Dubois. But she says that’s not necessarily a bad thing, ”Change is inevitable. Our world keeps changing and our event is going to keep changing because our world is changing.” She then joked that Burning Man is actually different every year. Burning Man now has cell service. Four towers were set up around Black Rock City this year so that those with Verizon or AT&amp;T can sends texts and call friends from one end of camp to the other…at least most of the time. Some camps also carry in their own Wi-Fi, but that’s mostly available for those just within that camp. Our world keeps changing and our event is going to keep changing.— Black Rock City manager Harley Dubois Harvey, who began the Burn on the beach with just a few friends 28 years ago, says the culture does change with the people, but that’s okay. As Harvey noted, “There’s this idea about the celebrities and billionaires but then there’s the other 99 percent. It’s not a quantitative problem it’s a qualitative problem.” He also notes that just a few years ago this event was mostly men. “Now our census says the percentage of men and women, Republicans to Democrats, is at a national norm now.” Even Republican leader Grover Norquist is reportedly at Burning Man this year. The Burning Man founders have pledged to get ahead of the news and be more proactive now that there’s been so much coverage, particularly in tech. “If we just sat back and did nothing it could be a bad thing, but when you get people with greater diversity. If we can change corporate America then we really can have an impact. It’s a dialogue that is happening between the new people that are coming and the old people who’ve been coming awhile,” said Dubois. Dubois tells me that tech people are welcome and bring in innovation. But she also admitted there was a certain VIP element happening. “That’s not okay,” she says. “It’s not in the spirit of Burning Man but we try to do what we can. Some people are just misinformed about what this is about. It’s hard for us to reach everyone.” Featured Image: jon collier/Flickr UNDER A CC BY-SA 2.0 LICENSE</Content></Article>