<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Cloudera Launches Paid Version Of Enterprise Data Management Software</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2010/06/29/cloudera-launches-paid-version-of-enterprise-data-management-software/</Url><Content>Cloudera, which is backed by an impressive list of investors and advisors and run by a team of experienced technology veterans, commercially distributes and services Hadoop. The startup is announcing its first paid software today: Cloudera Enterprise. Cloudera Enterprise is next generation data management software to help companies leverage the Apache Hadoop platform. Hadoop is a Java software framework born out of an open-source implementation of Google’s published computing infrastructure which is fostered within the Apache Software Foundation. Hadoop supports distributed applications running on large clusters of commodity computers processing enormous amounts of data. Cloudera helps distribute Hadoop, and provides services around the technology. The startup’s first paid subscription product, Cloudera Enterprise includes authorization management and provisioning, integration configuration and monitoring and resource management. Features include LDAP integration, which allows organizations to integrate directly with their existing user authentication system; delegated group administration so that separate groups can manage their own pool of users; application access control providing administrators with advanced control over data access and user logging so that administrators can review individual user activity for advanced security. Cloudera is also releasing a new version of its Distribution for Hadoop and has created two new open source projects as part of the distribution. The company is releasing Flume, its data loading infrastructure, and its Hadoop User Environment (HUE) code under the Apache V2 open source license. This is the first paid software for Cloudera. The company most recently launched a free desktop version, which provides a uniﬁed graphical user interface for Hadoop applications that includes tools for job and cluster management. Via Cloudera, Hadoop is currently used by most of the giants in the space including Google, Yahoo, Facebook (we wrote about Facebook’s use of Cloudera here), Amazon, AOL, Baidu and more. To date, Cloudera has raised $11 million in funding from Accel Partners and Greylock Partners. The company’s founder, Christophe Bisciglia, recently left Cloudera.</Content></Article>