<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Congratulations  Crunchies Winners  Kickstarter Wins Best Overall Startup</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/02/10/congratulations-crunchies-winners-kickstarter-wins-best-overall-startup/</Url><Content>It was a night for the ages. At the 7th Annual Crunchies Award show, Kickstarter beat out CloudFlare, Snapchat, Twitter and Uber, and walked away with the Crunchie for Best Overall Startup. Chris Sacca won the Crunchie For Angel Of The Year, Dropbox’s Drew Houston and Arash Ferdowsi won Founder of the Year, and Tinder took home Best New Startup. At the start of the show, John Oliver proclaimed, partly in jest, there are no losers at the Crunchies. “All the companies nominated are not losers,” Oliver states as only he can, “there are only companies that just failed to win.” We’re proud of all the nominees and applaud all the crazy innovations that startups and founders are constantly developing. Best Technology Achievement Apple A7 Processor – Runner-up Bitcoin – Winner Node.js Planet Labs low-cost satellites Project Loon Best Collaborative Consumption Service Airbnb – Winner Crowdtilt DogVacay Homejoy Lyft – Runner-up Best E-Commerce Application BarkBox Good Eggs Polyvore – Runner-up Warby Parker Wanelo – Winner Best Mobile Application Mailbox Snapchat – Winner Tinder VSCO Cam WhatsApp Vsco Cam – Runner-up Fastest Rising Startup Lulu QuizUp – Runner-up Tinder Upworthy – Winner Whisper Best Health Startup Fitbit MyFitnessPal One Medical Group – Winner Oscar – Runner-up Practice Fusion Best Design Exposure by Elepath Nest Protect Pencil by FiftyThree – Winner Hi Yahoo Weather – Runner-up Best Bootstrapped Startup Grammarly – Runner-up Imgur – Winner NerdWallet SmugMug TaskUs Sexiest Enterprise Startup Box ClearSlide New Relic – Runner-up Optimizely Zendesk – Winner Best International Startup BlaBlaCar – Runner-up Huddle Supercell Waze – Winner Xiaomi Best Education Startup Code.org – Runner-up CreativeLIVE Duolingo – Winner Khan Academy Treehouse Best Hardware Startup 3D Robotics – Runner-up Oculus VR – Winner SmartThings Sonos Square Can’t Stop, Won’t Stop Candy Crush Saga – Winner Netflix – Runner-up Tinder Vibease Vine Biggest Social Impact Code.org – Runner-up Crowdtilt Edward Snowden’s NSA Revelations – Winner StopWatching.Us Watsi Angel of the Year Steve Anderson Michael Dearing Keith Rabois Babak Nivi &amp; Naval Ravikant – Runner-up Chris Sacca – Winner VC of the Year Peter Fenton (Benchmark) – Winner Jim Goetz (Sequoia Capital) Reid Hoffman (Greylock Partners) Bill Maris (Google Ventures) Bijan Sabet (Spark Capital) – Runner-up Founder of the Year Arash Ferdowsi  &amp; Drew Houston (Dropbox) – Winner David Karp (Tumblr) Aaron Levie (Box) Lee Holloway , Matthew Prince &amp; Michelle Zatlyn(CloudFlare) – Runner-up Deena Varshavskaya (Wanelo) CEO of the Year Jeff Bezos (Amazon) Dick Costolo (Twitter) – Winner Travis Kalanick (Uber) – Runner-up Marissa Mayer (Yahoo!) Elon Musk (Tesla Motors &amp; SpaceX) Best New Startup of 2013 Anki Coinbase – Runner-up Glow Tinder – Winner Whisper Best Overall Startup of 2013 CloudFlare Kickstarter – Winner Snapchat Twitter Uber – Runner-up</Content></Article>