<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Congratulations Crunchies Winners  Dropbox Is The Best Overall Startup</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2012/01/31/crunchies-dropbox/</Url><Content>This year’s fifth annual Crunchies Awards has just finished up at the classy Davies Symphony Hall in San Francisco, and it was a smashing success. We poked fun #humblebraggers, got cussed at by Siri, honored former TechCrunch CEO Heather Harde, and gave wild monkey trophies to tech’s greatest innovators. If you missed the event or our livestream, check out the full list of nominees and winners below. The world owes a thank you to Jack Dorsey, the “Founder Of The Year” and leader of Twitter, winner of “Biggest Social Impact”. His poise and dedication helped keep the microblogging service online so it could aid revolutions. And a big congrats to Dropbox on its win for “Best Overall Startup”. The company’s young founders Drew Houston and Arash Ferdowsi (from right to left below) demonstrated the power of the freemium model, and had the guts to turn down a 9 figure acquisition bid. Here are the nominees and winners: Best Technology Achievement Lytro (Runner Up) NFC OnLive Siri (Winner) Tesla Flat Pack Battery Best Social Application Facebook Timeline Instagram (Runner Up) Google+ (Winner) The New New Twitter Path 2.0 Best Shopping Application Birchbox Fab  (Winner) Gilt Groupe Lot18 Warby Parker (Runner Up) Best Mobile Application Evernote (Winner) Flipboard (Runner Up) Pandora Spotify Square TaskRabbit Best Location Application Airbnb Foursquare Grindr (Winner) RunKeeper (Runner Up) Uber Best Tablet Application djay Eventbrite At the Door Fotopedia (Winner) GarageBand Netflix (Runner Up) StumbleUpon Best Design Gojee Orchestra Path 2.0  (Winner) Pinterest (Runner Up) Quora Best Bootstrapped Startup (2010 winner: addmired) Github (Runner Up) Imgur (Winner) Instapaper Onesheet Tap Tap Tap (Camera+) Best Cloud Service Asana Box (Runner Up) CloudFlare Dropbox (Winner) Okta Twilio Best International Startup Badoo Klarna (Runner Up) Peixe Urbano (Winner) Rovio SoundCloud Wonga Best Clean Tech Startup Alta Energy Array Power (Runner Up) EcoATM (Winner) EcoMotors Hara Best New Device Galaxy Nexus iPad 2 iPhone 4S Kindle Fire (Runner Up) Nest (Winner) Best Time Sink Modern Warfare 3 Quora Skyrim (Runner Up) Turntable.fm Words With Friends (Winner) Biggest Social Impact Charity: Water (Runner Up) Khan Academy Kickstarter Practice Fusion Twitter (Winner) Angel of the Year Ron Conway Paul Graham Reid Hoffman (Winner) Keith Rabois Naval Ravikant and Babak Nivi (Runner Up) Kevin Rose VC of the Year Marc Andreessen &amp; Ben Horowitz (Winner) Matt Cohler (Runner Up) Vinod Khosla Aileen Lee Yuri Milner David Sze Founder of the Year Leah Busque (Task Rabbit) Brian Chesky (Airbnb) Jack Dorsey (Square, Twitter) (Winner) Susan Feldman &amp; Ali Pincus (One Kings Lane) Drew Houston (Dropbox) (Runner Up) CEO of the Year Dick Costolo (Twitter) Daniel Ek (Spotify) (Runner Up) Phil Libin (Evernote) Mark Pincus (Zynga) Jeff Weiner (LinkedIn) (Winner) Best New Startup of 2011 Codecademy (Runner Up) Fab Nest Pinterest (Winner) Turntable.fm Best Overall Startup of 2011 Dropbox (Winner) Instagram Gilt Groupe Spotify Square (Runner Up) Tumblr Thanks to everyone who watched, voted, or attended the Crunchies. This award show is about the tech community, and we’re honored to have you as our readers.</Content></Article>