<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Custom T-Shirt Design App Snaptee Launches Partnership Program</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/27/snaptee-partnership/</Url><Content>Snaptee, the iOS and Android app that lets users design and order their own custom T-shirts, has launched a new revenue-sharing program for photo-editing and design app developers. The startup’s first beta partner is Manga Camera, a popular app that turns photos into comic book-like graphics. Snaptee, which is based in Hong Kong, also announced that its users have created over one million T-shirt designs since it launched in August 2013. Wai-Lun Hong, Snaptee’s CEO, says that the app currently has 300,000 registered users, most from the U.S., Japan, Germany, and UK. Right now Snaptee’s users can upload a photo or take one using its in-app camera and then edit it with Snaptee’s templates and filters. The partner program lets developers integrate Snaptee into their photo and design apps and share part of the revenue earned on any T-shirts purchased by their users. Hong says that most T-shirts created using Snaptee feature photos and text. For app developers who offer these features and currently rely on in-app purchases and ads for revenue, Hong believes Snaptee can offer a “more interesting way to monetize.” The partnership model is still experimental, but Hong told me that it will have a two-tier revenue sharing plan, with different amounts for new or return customers. “We offer a very attractive return for app developers bringing in new customers so we can both benefit from the partnership deal. And we are also happy to work closely with early partners to find the right model,” he says. Snaptee currently lets users print their custom designs on black and white T-shirts, hoodies, and sweatshirts. The app is available in English, Japanese, Korean, German, French, and simplified Chinese, and clothing can be shipped worldwide. Snaptee has received funding from Yat Siu of Outblaze Management Team and Animoca, Chris Lee of 6waves, Mikaal Abdulla from 8 Securities (a Techcrunch Disrupt Beijing finalist), Singapore-based angel investor Emanuel R. Breiter and Hong Kong-based investor Tytus Michalski of Fresco Capital.</Content></Article>