<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Disrupt SF Hackathon – More Prizes Than You Can Hack A Stick At</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/09/04/sf-disrupt-hackathon-more-prizes-than-you-can-hack-a-stick-at/</Url><Content>We’re fewer than 48 hours away from the start of the TechCrunch Disrupt SF Hackathon. To make your experience even better, we’ve partnered with some wonderful companies that have agreed to pony up some great prizes for best use of their systems. Clover Network  Clover, one of the fastest growing point of sale systems in the World has a robust collection of APIs, both Android and RESTful here: https://www.clover.com/docs The developer who builds the most interesting integration according to our panel of judges gets $5,000 and the opportunity to launch on the Clover Platform. Connect your apps to the merchant counter top in ways not possible before.  Extra credit if you use more than one API set from this conference. Clover has their engineering team on the floor and are available to answer questions at dev@clover.com Concur Best Use of Concur API — Up to $2,500 in Amazon Gift Cards – For an app that demonstrates the best use of Concur APIs; prize distribution is $200 to each winning team member. API Details at http://bit.ly/DisruptSF Best Use of Concur API + Co-Sponsor API On-stage – Free passes to The Perfect Trip DevCon 2014 ($99 per ticket) – For teams (2 tickets per team) that demonstrate the best of the Concur API + co-sponsor API onstage. For example, best use of Concur + Yodlee, Best use of Concur + Pebble, and so on. Applies to all Disrupt co-sponsors in the mashup ideas list at http://bit.ly/DisruptSF . All contestants can also apply to pitch their app for a shot at $100K in prizes. CrunchBase For best use of the CrunchBase API, PlayStation 4 for each member of the team for up to four (4) team members. DigitalOcean Participants must successfully use the DigitalOcean API in their hack: Prize 1 – TechCrunch Disrupt Hackathon 1st place winners: Win an all expenses paid 2 day trip to NYC. Hang out with DigitalOcean Team, meet with the founders and our team leads, ask questions and get coaching. PARROT AR.DRONE 2.0 for each participating team member $500 Apple Gift Card for each participating team member DigitalOcean Love Pack filled with sweatshirts and messenger bags $10,000 in DigitalOcean Credit Prize 2 – TechCrunch Disrupt Hackathon 2nd place winners: PARROT AR.DRONE 2.0 for each participating team member $500 Apple Gift Card for each participating team member DigitalOcean Love Pack filled with sweatshirts, messenger bags and flasks $5,000 in DigitalOcean credit Prize 3 – TechCrunch Disrupt Hackathon 3rd place winners: PARROT AR.DRONE 2.0 for each participating team member DigitalOcean Love Pack filled with sweatshirts, messenger bags and flasks $1,000 in DigitalOcean credit Esri Win $2500 prize for best use of Esri’s ArcGIS software plus free year one year subscription to ArcGIS Online. Here are a few examples of what one year ArcGIS Online subscription delivers: Geocoding Infographics GeoEnrichment Directions &amp; Routing Custom Tile Storage Unlimited Place Serach Geotrigger (Geofencing) Map draws – up to 1,000,000 per month And more…  Check out https://developers.arcgis.com &amp; https://github.com/Esri  EVO Snap* Hack and Win! EVO Snap* is giving away a brand new 2014 Honda Metropolitan to the developer who demonstrates the most creative and/or innovate use of the Snap* APIs in their Hackathon creation. Saving gas is a Snap* with this stylish 49cc Honda scooter that delivers up to 100 MPG! Capture the attention of the EVO Snap* team and you could ride off in the comfy saddle of a beautiful Candy Orange/Pearl Black Metropolitan featuring an ergonomic design, modern instrument panel and 22 liters of lockable beneath-the-seat storage. Visit the EVO Snap* booth on-site for details and eligibility requirements. Frequentz Technology leader Frequentz, is offering up $5000 in prize money for the most innovative app, utilizing Bluemix, to enhance its global tracking and tracing capabilities. Frequentz’s software solutions provide valuable end-to-end data insights across the Life Sciences, Food, CPG, and Industrial marketplace to assure Brand Integrity &amp; Customer Safety. API Documentation can be found here. Golgi Speed up development time by using the Golgi SDK for deep linking content, managing device connectivity, ensuring cross platform compatibility, creating two-way cloud communication and launching push notifications with one simple solution. Prize for team who makes best Golgi App: Choice between iPad Mini or Nexus 7 or $500 Amazon Gift Card 1 year of premium service on Golgi Become our Promotional App on our 10-city Golgi Tour IdeaMarket Best Idea Market Project: Projects that are built using Idea Market ideas have a chance to win $3000.  All entries are eligible to win funding from investors.  Project list can be found at: http://ideamarket.me/disrupt Intel Mashery For the best use of Intel Mashery APIs and/or Intel Galileo hardware, each team member (up to 5) will each receive: (1) super hero wearable blanket and (1) Basis Health Tracker smart watch. MasterCard OpenAPI Developer Engagement Incentives MasterCard is challenging developers to use its APIs during the TechCrunch Disrupt Hackathon. The prizes below will be awarded independently from the TechCrunch judging and decided by MasterCard employees present during the event. Access our APIs through the MasterCard Developer Zone. Prizes: Best use of MasterCard API: a $400 MasterCard gift card for each team member (up to 4 members) Prize Power-Ups: +$100 per team member if the Simplify Commerce API is used +$300 per team member if two MasterCard API services are used Best use of MasterCard API runner-up: $200 MasterCard gift card for each team member (up to 4 members) MasterCard will also be providing promotional items for developers throughout the event. Register here: https://developer.mastercard.com/plugins/user-registration/user-registration.action Microsoft Ventures Best Use of Azure: Microsoft will award to the best use of Microsoft technology including the Express framework, Node.js and Azure, one Surface 3 per team member up to 4. Moxtra Three winners for best use of Moxtra SDK/APIs All three winning teams get Mentorship via Moxtra with Subrah Iyer, co-founder of Moxtra and WebEx All three winning teams get 1 year free unlimited use of Moxtra SDK in their app, if they decide to commercialize the Hackathon app All three winning teams get cash reward; $1000 for first place and $500 for second and third place Old Navy Old Navy believes that technology innovation can continue to enhance the consumer shopping experience and we are looking for creative, technology based approaches to help us in this effort.  Old Navy will be giving its branded mobile app a complete overhaul which should be completed by the end of 2014 or early 2015, which will be promoted heavily once live.  Details of the new app features cannot be disclosed at this point, however, we are looking for potential solutions that can integrate into the app that would be able to create a more seamless, user-friendly shopping experience. A problem that we are specifically trying to solve for is: How can we use technology to create something that better bridges the experience between pre-shopping, shopping, and post shopping. Challenge:  Old Navy stores are currently equipped with iBeacons, and we are looking for great, creative, and useful solutions that can leverage iBeacon technology in a way that will make the shopping experience for our customers more unique, personalized, fun, and exciting.  Pending final submissions, the winning idea/solution could be integrated into the new brand app launching soon. This provides general background and guidance, but we are also open to other ideas/solutions outside of the direction given above. PayPal_Braintree For the most innovative use of Braintree / Venmo / PayPal, each member of the winning team will come home with a XYZprinting Da Vinci 1.0 3D Printer and accessories. Pearson The $500 amazon gift card will be awarded to the team with the best implementation of one or more of Pearson’s APIs. These include Acclaim (an open badging platform, https://www.youracclaim.com ), LearningStudio (a Learning Management System platform, http://pdn.pearson.com ), as well as the Pearson content APIs (Dictionaries, Financial Times, https://developer.pearson.com) Peel Best implementation of our APIs wins $2,000.  Runner-up $1,000.  Everyone using gets Peel T-shirt and hacky sack for each team member. Sabre Best use of Sabre APIs wins $2,500   https://developer.sabre.com/docs/read/REST_APIs  Sinch Sinch is offering a $5,000 prize for the most creative use of its calling and messaging SDK at the TechCrunch Hackathon. For a tutorial on how to implement JavaScript messaging, please visit:http://tutorial.sinch.com/js-messaging-tutorial/. For a tutorial on how developers can implement its new JavaScript calling, please visit here: http://tutorial.sinch.com/js-calling-tutorial/. Developers can also tweet Sinch @SinchDev or email dev@sinch.com with any questions. Spark We’ll have two winners! First place gets choice of prize: Hacker’s Paradise: A $500 gift card courtesy of SparkFun for any and all components and tools you want on their site + a whole bunch of Spark gear or All of the Smart Home Things: Nest, Fitbit Aria, Lockitron, Dropcam + Powered by Spark products from Lono, CleverPet, Nomiku &amp; of course some Spark gear  Plus the Spark team will be around and willing to do mini-Kickstarter consultations with any Internet of Things projects. Twilio For the best use of the Twilio API, Three Apple Smart Watches (to be announced) Twitter Twitter’s prizes will go to the team with the most interesting use of Twitter’s API. Awards include: Secret Prize to be announced at awards 4 Jambox MInis 4 iPod Touches Grab bag for each teammate of Twitter swag UX Awards UX Award for the Best UX at the TechCrunch Disrupt Hackathon, September 7, 2014 Versal Create a Versal gadget and help bring interactivity to online learning. Versal is opening up our developer platform, enabling JavaScript developers to build interactive learning apps called “gadgets”. Gadgets are embeddable apps that teachers around the world use to create cool courses within the Versal platform. From interactive diagrams and timelines to games and simulations, developers are limited only by their imagination. Gadgets can be developed in our Web-based IDE, or the SDK can be downloaded to your own environment. At the TechCrunch Disrupt hackathon, we’ll award the following to the best gadget submitted by the end of the event: a Chromebook (up to two if you have multiple teammates), plus a $2500 contract to complete the gadget. It will also be featured in the Versal course creator for teachers to use in their courses.  Weather Underground Win with weather!  We’re awarding $1,000 cash to the most interesting and best use of weather data in a hack.  The Weather Underground weather API is easy to implement and scalable across any platform. Sign up for your free developer key here: http://www.wunderground.com/weather/api/d/pricing.html Yammer We’re giving away the prizes (XBox One, Windows Phones) to the best hack submission that incorporates Yammer data via the Yammer Platform API at http://dev.yammer.com. Yodlee Interactive The grand prize winner will also receive Beats by Dre speakers courtesy of Yodlee Interactive.</Content></Article>