<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Dogpatch Labs SF Moves From Pier 38 To Palo Alto  Opens New Accelerator In Dublin</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/29/dogpatch-labs-sf-moves-from-pier-38-to-palo-alto-opens-new-accelerator-in-dublin/</Url><Content>As you may have heard, the San Francisco Port Authority recently shut down the tech hub located at Pier 38, which was home to companies like Automattic, True Ventures, 99Designs, and others. One of the tenants, Polaris Venture Partners‘ Dogpatch Labs, was also kicked out and has now moved to downtown Palo Alto along with its 18 current residents. Xconomy reports that Dogpatch Labs’ new Palo Alto home is adjacent to the also new Polaris Venture Partners office (the might want to update their website if this is indeed the case). The address is 151 Lytton Street. More interestingly, Dogpatch Labs has also set up its first international startup accelerator. The new facility is located in Dublin, Ireland, more specifically in the ‘Warehouse’ building on Barrow Street, beside Google’s Europlex. Says Terry McGuire, cofounder and general partner at Polaris Venture Partners: “The Dogpatch Labs initiative has led to the successful launch of several important companies including Instagram, Formspring, JIBE and Thing Labs. Since the inception of Dogpatch Labs, more than 100 companies have received funding in excess of $140 million. Thirteen companies have already been acquired. We are extremely proud of the entrepreneurs in our network and look forward to establishing relationships with technology entrepreneurs in Europe.” Polaris has named Noel Ruane to the role of Entrepreneur-in-Residence for Dogpatch Labs Europe. Ruane previously led and managed LaunchPad, an accelerator program for tech startups in Dublin. Earlier in his career, Ruane was VP Business Development for IDA Ireland in Mountain View, California, where he was the overseas officer responsible for attracting tech companies like Google, Yahoo, Amazon, Ebay and Paypal to Ireland. Aside from Palo Alto and Dublin, Dogpatch Labs can also be found in New York and Cambridge, Massachusetts.</Content></Article>