<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Dropbox Is Now iOS 8-Ready With A Notification Center Widget  App Extension Support And More</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/09/23/dropbox-is-now-ios-8-ready-with-a-notification-center-widget-app-extension-support-and-more/</Url><Content>Now that iOS 8 is on the loose, Apple users are receiving much-improved versions of their favorite apps, designed to take advantage of new iOS features – like the ability to create custom widgets in the Notification Center. Today, file-sharing application Dropbox has rolled out its iOS 8 upgrade, which now includes a new Notification Center widget of its own, offering a quick overview of your files and recent changes. Other new features make it easier to manage folders, connect to Dropbox from other apps, and control permissions for end users if on Dropbox for Business or Dropbox Pro. With the upgrade, the biggest change is that Dropbox can now be added to the iOS 8 Notification Center, providing a view of your most important files, including both those associated with your business and your personal files, if applicable. For those with only business or only personal files, you’ll just see a single list, instead of three separate tabs (All Personal, Business). In the widget, you can track newly added files, as well as changes like renamed files and edits. And with a tap on a file name, you can quickly launch Dropbox without needing to locate the app on your phone. Another change in the new app involves Shared Folders, which can now be created and managed on the go from the Dropbox app on iPhone and iPad. This addition is less about taking advantage of something iOS 8 specifically offers, and is rather about rolling out a feature users have been demanding for some time. You can now share the link to a folder from an action menu in the app, or invite users to a folder and manage their access levels. Also, because iOS 8 supports app extensions, you’ll now be able to import and export files to and from other iOS apps that support Apple’s “Storage Provider App Extensions” functionality. In order to import files to Dropbox, you’ll need to tap on the ellipsis icon (…) at the top of your file list, then choose “More” and toggle on or off the Dropbox as an option under “Manage Storage Providers.” And finally, for Business or Pro users, the iOS 8 update brings the ability to set and manage read-only permissions on shared folders via the Dropbox app, for control over what’s being shared – another more minor (but useful) feature, but again unrelated to Apple’s iOS 8 improvements. The updated app is now live on iTunes.</Content></Article>