<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Etsy Buys French Startup A Little Market In Its Largest Acquisition So Far</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/23/etsy-buys-french-startup-a-little-market-in-its-largest-acquisition-so-far/</Url><Content>Etsy announced today that it has acquired a French company called A Little Market, a Paris-based online marketplace for handmade items. Though terms of the deal were undisclosed, Etsy says that this is its “sixth and largest acquisition to date.” A Little Market will continue to operate independently. Previous acquisitions by Etsy, which has received $97.3 million in funding so far from Accel Partners, Union Square Ventures, and other investors, have included Trunkt, which specializes in selling artisanal goods wholesale; digital advertising company Adtuitive; and Etsy Lovers. One of Etsy’s previous founding rounds, in which it raised $40 million led by Index Ventures in May 2012, was earmarked specifically for international expansion. In its A Little Market announcement, Etsy, which currently claims more than 40 million members, said at least 25% of its orders are shipped internationally. “As we’ve focused on international growth, capitalizing on the strongest economies in the world has been a top priority. France is the fifth largest economy and seventh largest e-commerce market globally, and it is Etsy’s strongest non-English market,” the company said in a statement. It added that its business in France is more than 90% import/export and that Little Market, where most goods are sold domestically, will complement its existing business. We asked Etsy about their future acquisition plans and a spokesperson told us: “As we grow, we’ll always consider our options to build, buy or partner, seeking partnerships or acquisitions that are highly mission-aligned as well as high performance. We have no specific plans for other acquisitions, but we’re always paying attention to the landscape and meeting with teams we respect and admire.” Image from A Little Market vendor Karmeli’s store</Content></Article>