<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>FullContact Raises $7 Million  Rolls Out A New Universal Contacts App For iOS</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2015/01/29/fullcontact-raises-7-million-rolls-out-a-new-universal-contacts-app-for-ios/</Url><Content>FullContact, a company offering a range of solutions for contact management for both consumers and developers alike, has raised an additional $7 million in Series B funding, it announced this morning alongside the launch of a new universal contacts app for iOS. The round was led by prior investor Foundry Group, and included participation from another earlier investor 500 Startups as well as Blue Note Ventures. Blue Note Ventures is the new fund from Chris Marks, who, as a partner at High Country Venture, had invested in FullContact in an earlier round. So the investor is the same, but the vehicle differs, to be clear. With the new funding, FullContact has raised just under $16 million to date. More recently, FullContact has been working to roll out more tools aimed at the consumer market. Last month, for example, it debuted the FullContact for Gmail plugin. This browser add-on competes with LinkedIn’s Rapportive, offering a sidebar in Gmail showing a contacts’ name, information and even their social media posts. Unfortunately, that service as of today fails to pull in a lot of data, we found, due to the fact that it’s limited by what it call pull in from LinkedIn thanks to LinkedIn’s API restrictions. Though Rapportive users haven’t always been happy about the changes made since the service was acquired by LinkedIn, its access to LinkedIn’s data still makes it one to beat, it seems. That may change in time, however, as FullContact improves upon its own contacts database. Today, FullContact is expanding its lineup of consumer products once again, with the launch of FullContact for iPhone and FullContact for iPad. The new apps have been developed using the technology from Cobook, a startup FullContact acquired a year ago. Updates Updated Contact Settings1 Settings 2 Search-Display Hamburger Menu  View Slideshow Previous Next Exit Like Cobook before, FullContact for iOS creates universal contact entries for those in your address book by combining the data you have stored on your device with information from Google, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, AngelList and more. The service now syncs this data between Google, your iPhone or iPad and FullContact’s web service. The app includes a lot useful contact management features, like the ability to add photos to entries, merge duplicates, add more social profiles, use swipe gestures (to call, email, message, tag, etc.), sort contacts by name, date created or modified, date contacted and more. It also auto-updates entries when new information becomes available, and can transcribe business cards, turning them into iPhone contacts. The company doesn’t disclose exact numbers with regard to its customer base, growth or revenue, but will say that the Cobook app it acquired, and is now transitioning to the new brand and feature set, has seen “millions of downloads.” That means that the app is likely still installed on a number of devices already, and those users are today being automatically upgraded to FullContact’s new product. FullContact also says that it’s seeing overall growth numbers that are “significantly above industry standards.” Currently, the company generates revenue via its API business, but that’s changing over the course of the next 18 to 24 months as FullContact expands its solution to other platforms, including Android and Mac. The new FullContact for iOS app will be live here on iTunes today, taking over Cobook’s spot. (Note: if you’re still seeing the Cobook app, you’ll just need to wait for iTunes to propagate the change to all servers, which should be shortly.)</Content></Article>