<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>GitHub Partners With DigitalOcean  Unreal Engine  Others To Give Students Free Access To Developer Tools</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/10/07/github-partners-with-digital-ocean-unreal-engine-and-others-to-give-students-free-access-to-developer-tools/</Url><Content>Back in the days of shrink-wrapped software, students would often get huge discounts on expensive software packages like Adobe’s Creative Suite or Microsoft’s developer tools. But because almost every developer startup has now moved to a SaaS model, it’s become a bit harder to find student discounts. To help students start new software projects without breaking the bank, GitHub, Bitnami, Crowdflower, DigitalOcean, DNSimple, HackHands, Namecheap, Orchestrate, Screenhero, SendGrid, Stripe, Travis CI and Epic Game’s Unreal Engine are launching the GitHub Student Developer Pack, a new program to give students free access to their tools. A GitHub spokesperson told me that the company already has about 100,000 students on its free plan, but with the Developer Pack, they can now get free access to a GitHub micro account (usually $7/month) with up to five private repositories for as long as they are students. The other companies offer similar benefits — some for a year and some for as long as the student (13+) is enrolled in school. Unreal Engine is giving students free access to its $19/month subscription service, while Digital Ocean is making $100 worth of credit on its platform available to students. And once their project makes money, they can use Stripe to collect payments with fees waived on the first $1,000. Overall, this looks like a pretty good program for students who want to get their first projects off the ground. Together with the free tiers on AWS, Azure and other platform, the GitHub Pack should give most students enough resources to get a pretty complex project off the ground. To get access to the pack, students either need a school email address, valid student ID or some other proof of enrollment (enrollment letter, transcript, etc.). Students with existing GitHub student accounts will also automatically get access to the developer pack. Here is a full list of all the benefits: Bitnami Install cloud applications in a single click Business 3 plan (normally $49/month) for one year Crowdflower Crowdsourcing and data enrichment platform Access to the Crowdflower platform (normally $2,500/month) and $50 in worker credit. DigitalOcean Simple cloud hosting, built for developers $100 in platform credit DNSimple Simple DNS management with one-click services and a robust API Bronze hosted DNS plan (normally $3/month) for two years GitHub Powerful collaboration, code review, and code management for open source and private projects Micro account (normally $7/month) with five private repositories while you’re a student HackHands Live programming help available 24/7 $25 in platform credit Namecheap Domain name registration and SSL certificates one year free domain name registration on the .me TLD (normally 8.99/year) and one year free SSL certificate (normally $9/year) Orchestrate Unified database as a service including search, key/value, graph, and events Developer account (normally $49/month) while you’re a student Screenhero Screen sharing for collaboration in teams Individual account (normally $9.99/month) while you’re a student SendGrid Email infrastructure as a service Student plan (normally $4.95/month) for one year Stripe Web and mobile payments, built for developers Waived transaction fees on first $1000 in revenue processed Travis CI Continuous integration platform for the open source and private projects Private builds (normally $69/month) while you’re a student Unreal Engine A complete suite of game development tools made by game developers, for game developers Unreal Engine (normally $19/month) while you’re a student</Content></Article>