<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Google Announces The Top Apps  Movies  Music Of 2014</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/12/11/google-announces-the-top-apps-movies-music-of-2014/</Url><Content>Google has just released its ‘best stuff of the year’ on Google Play for 2014, and in terms of most downloaded content, it’s not all that different from Apple’s list. Frozen, The Walking Dead, and Fancy by Iggy Azalea all placed at the top of the list in their respective categories, though the app situation varied a bit from that of Apple’s list, which is an editorial decision while Google focuses on downloads. In the Google Play store, top apps included Duolingo (which made Apple’s list last year), Netflix, Facebook, and MyFitness Pal to name a few. Google also said that Health and Fitness was the fastest growing app category. Here’s the full list from Google. Congrats to the folks who are on it. APPS Most Downloaded Apps by Category in 2014 Education: Duolingo Health &amp; Fitness: MyFitnessPal Music: Pandora Photography:Flipagram Social: Facebook Entertainment: Netflix Sports:NFL Mobile Travel: TripAdvisor The Year’s Fastest Growing App Category Health &amp; Fitness GAMES Top Downloaded Games in 2014 Candy Crush Saga Don’t Tap The White Tile Farm Heroes Saga Subway Surfers Clash of Clans Feature: Achievements Play Games users unlocked 3.5 billion achievements this year MOVIES &amp; TV Movie of the year: Frozen TV show of the year: The Walking Dead Comeback Movie: Toy Story Most searched actor on Google Play: Robin Williams MUSIC Album of the Year: Frozen: Original Motion Picture Soundtrack Song of the Year: Dark Horse by Katy Perry Song of the Summer: Fancy by Iggy Azalea Fastest Growing Genre: Soundtracks (fueled by Frozen, Guardians of the Galaxy, Despicable Me 2, The Lego Movie and The Great Gatsby soundtracks) NEWSSTAND News Sources of the Year: The New York Times TMZ Forbes Now The Verge The Huffington Post The Daily Beast The Wall Street Journal Gizmodo Android Central Some of the most read articles of 2014: Flavorpill – 15 ’90s Teen Heartthrobs Who’ve Resurfaced on TV Mental Floss – 50 More Awesome Facts (About Everything) MarketWatch – 10 most miserable cities in America Houzz – Bathroom Workbook: How Much Does a Bathroom Remodel Cost? The Verge – The Verge Awards: the best of CES 2014 BOOKS Books of the Year: The Fault in Our Stars Fifty Shades of Grey Divergent Twelve Years a Slave Insurgent Here’s a link to the exact same list as you see above.</Content></Article>