<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Google Returning Month Of December To Nexus Devices With Android 4 2 1 OTA Update</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2012/11/27/google-now-returning-month-of-december-to-nexus-devices-with-android-4-2-1-ota-update/</Url><Content>Google is in the process of rolling out Android 4.2.1 to at least Nexus 4 and Nexus 10 devices (with Nexus 7 and Galaxy Nexus hardware likely to follow) as an over-the-air update, Android Central reports. The minor update brings a fix for an embarrassing omission on Google’s part: The month of December. December was left out of the People app, meaning it couldn’t be chosen as either a birthday or anniversary for contacts on Android 4.2 devices. December was missing from the Android date picker for certain functions, though luckily not for the Calendar app, meaning you could still set appointments or block off your Christmas vacation. But the bug was nonetheless a fairly significant oversight, and one that brought a lot of derision from the user community and media. Google reportedly checked out the issue as soon as it became public, though didn’t officially note it until the company promised a fix a few days later on November 20. When Google finally copped to the bug, Frederic noted that it took the company quite a while to even officially acknowledge that the easily verified bug existed, but roughly two weeks from bug identification to pushing out a fix actually isn’t that bad of a timeline at all. Now, a week after that, users are seeing the update roll out OTA to their devices, which apparently brings little else to the table beyond zapping the December bug. The update is being rolled out gradually, as is generally the case with new versions of Android, so don’t worry if you aren’t seeing it yet. One other interesting tidbit: Android Central says this doesn’t appear to break the loophole that allows users to activate LTE on their Nexus 4 for band 4 frequencies, like those used in Canada. Which is great news, because that’s a feature I’m pretty interested in keeping, maybe more so than December.</Content></Article>