<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Google Inbox Invite Hits eBay</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/10/23/google-inbox-invite-hits-ebay/</Url><Content>On a scale from one to ten, how desperate are you to try out Google’s new Inbox app? Would you pay for it? eBay user bpatel90, who has listed the invite on the online auction platform, will sell you an invite right now for around $50. Google’s Inbox is a newly announced mobile app that is meant to totally replace the way you used to deal with your email. It was released as a limited invite-only beta, and isn’t something you can simply find on the Play store or App Store just yet. The app was built by the folks who created Gmail, but is meant to be entirely different from Gmail, pulling from pieces of Google Now and even Mailbox. Inbox bundles certain emails together, like receipts and reservations, automatically so that you don’t have to spend time hunting down something specific from a long time ago. Not surprisingly, Inbox will also try to identify what’s important to you based on date and time to make sure that the most relevant information is highlighted. For example, if you’re headed to the airport for a flight, Inbox will make sure that your flight itinerary information is highlighted within the app. It will even go so far as to display real-time flight updates and other important information that may not be included directly within the emails. And not unlike Mailbox, Google’s new Inbox app lets you snooze certain messages and create to-do lists from your email, helping you be as productive as possible. With features like this, it makes sense that someone would post their invite up to eBay. No one likes email. It’s this sad, necessary evil of the internet. So if you want to try something new in the hopes that it will solve your email woes, the eBay deal isn’t necessarily a bad one. Or… you could harass the people in your Twitter feed who seem to already have the app. Invite? pic.twitter.com/53AHrloxFz — Jay Yarow (@jyarow) October 23, 2014 If you’re still just finding out what Google Inbox is (don’t feel bad… it was only announced yesterday), you can check out the official Google announcement here, or watch the video below.</Content></Article>