<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Greylock Partners Opens Up Applications For Its Second Hackfest</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2012/09/10/greylock-partners-opens-up-applications-for-its-second-hackfest/</Url><Content>After a successful first Hackathon series, VC firm Greylock Partners has announced Hackfest II, to continue the mission of building a network of interns and talent to build great companies and products. Greylock offers the typical mentor program that you’d find in other incubators and hackathons, but the caliber of those involved is unmatched. This isn’t your every day 24-hour hackathon. The first Hackfest was hosted by Instagram’s Kevin Systrom, Greylock’s Reid Hoffman, Mike Schroepfer of Facebook and Mike Olson of CLoudera. Those participating were interns from some of the hottest startups in Silicon Valley, and totaled over 150. Winners were able to go to dinner with Reid Hoffman and received $3K in Amazon Web Service credits. Of course, Reid Hoffman joined the stage at TechCrunch Disrupt today, and spoke with Michael Arrington about what he’s up to these days. This second Hackfest is built upon campus communication that happens completely online. When you think about college programs, you think about on-campus communication, but this is the Internet after-all. It’s incredibly difficult to get into the program, I was told by Greylock, but that just means that the firm wants to attract the best-of-the-best. Applications are open now for college interns who want to get involved: Given the huge success of greylock hackfest, we’ve decided to host another similar event on July 27-28, 2013. We will be posting more details about greylock hackfest 2 in the months to come, but you can count on interacting with more amazing mentors and judges from the Greylock community. Over the course of the year, we will be partnering with on-campus hackathons, such as PennApps, offering automatic entry in Greylock Hackfest 2 to the winning teams. If you’re organizing an on-campus hackathon, please contact Julie Deroche. We’d love to ensure your university’s best and brightest hackers find their way to greylock hackfest 2. Here’s a video from the first Hackfest that happened this past summer: [Photo credit: Flickr]</Content></Article>