<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Hands On With Xiaomi’s Mi Note Phablet</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2015/01/15/mi-note-hands-on/</Url><Content>China’s Xiaomi outed its latest smartphone, the Mi Note, yesterday, and we briefly managed to get our mitts on the 5.7-inch screen device. As the first phablet in Xiaomi’s flagship Mi family, it is pretty easy to make a comparison with the iPhone 6+. Indeed, CEO Lei Jun did compare the specs of the two phones during the launch event, but there are plenty of differences between the two. The Mi Note uses curved glass to give it graceful edges, the phone actually has glass fronts on both sides, and its camera — which sports an OIC — doesn’t stick out as it does on the Apple device. There’s also a whopping 3,000 mAh battery to help the phone last as long as possible, though we haven’t had a chance to do a takeaway review of its capacity at this point. The Mi Note feels great in the hand. This phone is seriously wafer thin at just 6.95mm thick and 161g in weight, but yet the build quality is sturdy. At 2,299 CNY ($370) for a 16GB model and 2,799 (circa $450) for the 64GB version, the device adheres to Xiaomi’s super-competitive approach to price — even the specc’ed up Mi Note Pro will retail for 3,299 CNY ($535), that’s roughly half the cost of a top of the range iPhone 6+ unlocked. xiaomi mi note05 xiaomi mi note06 xiaomi mi note07 xiaomi mi note01 xiaomi mi note02 xiaomi mi note03 xiaomi mi note04 xiaomi mi note08 xiaomi mi note09 xiaomi mi note10 xiaomi mi note11 xiaomi mi note12 xiaomi mi note13 xiaomi mi note14 xiaomi mi note15 xiaomi mi note16 xiaomi mi note19  View Slideshow Previous Next Exit There’s no word on when the new devices will appear in overseas markets at this point. Xiaomi sells its phones in seven countries, but it has plans to expand that number in 2015, most likely to Brazil, Turkey, Russia and other parts of Southeast Asia. If you’re not living in those places, you’re limited to marveling at these phones from afar, unfortunately. Bonus photos: Xiaomi also revealed a new set of $80 headphones. Don’t expect to see them sold outside of China soon/perhaps ever though. IMGP6756 IMGP6755 IMGP6676 IMGP6759 IMGP6735  View Slideshow Previous Next Exit</Content></Article>