<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Hands On With The HTC One (M8) For Windows</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/08/19/hands-on-with-the-htc-one-m8-for-windows/</Url><Content>The HTC One (M8), one of the best-looking flagship Android smartphones that launched earlier this year, just landed on Windows Phone 8.1.1 Packed with front-facing speakers, dual UltraPixel cameras on the back, a 5MP front camera and BoomSound internal speakers, the One (M8) is exactly the same as its Android variant. When you think of most Windows Phones, you picture the flashy and colorful Nokia Lumia devices, but the sleek, brushed metallic design of the HTC One (M8) gives consumers a new alternative to the Windows Phone OS. The only difference in terms of hardware is that the Windows variant will ship with 32GB, as opposed to the 16GB and 32GB options on Android. DSC_9928 DSC_9926 DSC_9924  View Slideshow Previous Next Exit 5.0-inch, 1080p display 2.3GHz Qualcomm Snapdragon 801 quad-core processor 2GB RAM, 32GB storage MicroSD expandable storage 5MP front camera, HTC UltraPixel rear camera 802.11ac, Bluetooth 4.0 Full specs can be found here. The HTC camera app replaces the Nokia camera software that usually comes packed in Windows Phones, but a stock camera app is still available. HTC’s app uses a depth sensor and dual cameras to add more perspective in pictures and lets you refocus a shot after you take it. Overall, you’ll find a similar experience to most flagship Windows Phones. You’ll find Cortana, the Windows Phone personal assistant, and a host of HTC apps, replacing the idea of a “skin” as you would usually find on an Android phone. The Windows Phone version also includes Blinkfeed, a home screen news reader on Android which acts like a news aggregator just a tap away on the Windows Phone. It supports the popular Dot View case, which lets you access notifications at the touch of a finger without opening the phone case. The HTC One M8 for Windows Phone is available on Verizon at noon today for $99.99 with a two-year contract, or you can use Verizon Edge to grab it for $29.99 per month. You can pick up at retail stores tomorrow.</Content></Article>