<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Here Is Apple’s Mailer Asking Cupertino Residents To Support Its New Campus Ahead Of City Council Vote</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2013/10/11/here-is-apples-mailer-asking-cupertino-residents-to-support-its-new-campus-ahead-of-city-council-vote/</Url><Content>If you live in Cupertino, you might have received a little gift from Apple in the mail: a brochure asking for support for its new headquarters, which the company calls “Apple Campus 2.” The circular building has become famous even before becoming real, due mostly to its striking design and massive size. The complex, when complete, will house around 13,000 of Apple’s employees. On October 15th, the City Council of Cupertino will vote on the project. If approved, a second vote in November will be required to certify the decision. Apple, in its pamphlet, stated that, following approval, it will move quickly to dig in. Here’s the inside and outside of the mailer: If I were a betting man, I would wager that Apple’s bid will be approved. Its pull in its hometown is not small, and the design of the campus is, frankly, beautiful. But even Apple, a company that could probably buy its home city in cash, has to win over the hearts and minds of the residents that don’t currently work for it. We’ll know soon enough if it will work. Then it will be time for shovels. Maybe. – Here’s the full text of the note, if you don’t want to squint: Dear Neighbor, It’s been a long journey since Steve Jobs first presented his vision for Apple Campus 2 to the Cupertino City Council in June 2011. As Steve said then, Apple has always been in Cupertino. It’s been our headquarters and our home, and we want to remain and grow here. A video of the presentation, posted on Cupertino’s website, has received over 1,800,000 views worldwide. Since the initial presentation, we have reached out to the community in a number of ways, and we are truly humbled by the overwhelming support and many expressions of goodwill we have received. Thanks you. We’re now in the final stages of the permitting process, and a key meeting is fast approaching. The City Council meeting to consider the project is scheduled for October 15 at 5:00 p.m. It will be held at Cupertino Community Hall, 10350 Torre Avenue. We would be grateful if you could share your support for Apple Campus 2 by emailing the City Council at citycouncil@cupertino.org and by attending the October 15 meeting as well. As always, please let us know if you have any questions or comments by emailing us at applecampus2@apple.com. We plan to break ground shortly after approval. We will keep in touch as construction progresses, and we look forward to welcoming all of you to a community day when our beautiful new home opens in 2016. Thank you again for your continued interest in Apple and your support for Apple Campus 2. Best regards, Peter Oppenheimer SVP and Chief Financial Officer Apple Top Image Credit: Apple</Content></Article>