<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Here Are The Official Specs For The Nexus 4 And Nexus 10</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/29/here-are-the-official-specs-for-the-nexus-4-and-nexus-10/</Url><Content>When Google announced the Nexus 4 and the Nexus 10, they neglected to mention specific specifications for folks who specifically wanted them. Luckily, we just got our hands on a nice, complete list. As we noted, the N10 has a 5MP front camera and 1.9MP back camera and 2GB RAM. It’s running a Dual-core A15 Eagle processor and runs for up to 500 hours on standby. The N4 has a 8MP back camera and 1.3MP front camera, 2GB RAM, and Qualcomm Snapdragon S4 Pro 1.5GHz processor. It has a 4.7-inch 1280×768 pixel screen. It also includes a wireless charging solution that is compatible with the Qi inductive charging standard. Read on for the full run-down. Nexus 10 Screen 10.055” 2560 x 1600 (300 ppi) WQXGA, HD PLS Corning® Gorilla® Glass 2 Size W: 10.39 in (263.9 mm) H: 6.99 in (177.6 mm) D: 0.35 in (8.9 mm) Weight 1.33 lbs (603 g) Cameras 5MP (main), 1080p video 1.9MP (front), 720p video Memory 16 GB or 32 GB (formatted capacity will be less) CPU/GPU CPU: Dual-core A15 Eagle GPU: Mali T604 RAM 2GB Sensors Accelerometer, Compass, Ambient light, Gyroscope, Pressure, GPS Wireless Dual-band Wi-Fi 802.11 b/g/n (MIMO+HT40) Bluetooth Dual-side NFC (Android Beam) Connectivity Micro USB Micro HDMI 3.5mm headphone jack Battery 9,000 mAh Lithium polymer Standby: up to 500 hours Music playback: up to 90 hours Video playback: up to 9 hours Web browsing: up to 7 hours OS Android 4.2 (Jelly Bean) Nexus 4 Screen 4.7” 1280×768 (320ppi) WXGA, HD IPS+ Corning® Gorilla® Glass 2 Size H: 5.27 in (133.9 mm) W: 2.7 in (68.7 mm) D: 0.36 in (9.1 mm) Weight 0.31 lbs (139 g) Cameras Main: 8MP BSI sensor, 1080p video Front: 1.3MP, 720p video Face recognition Memory 8GB or 16GB (formatted capacity will be less) Chipset Qualcomm Snapdragon S4 Pro 1.5GHz (Adreno 320 GPU) RAM 2GB Sensors Accelerometer, Compass, Ambient light, Proximity, Gyroscope, Pressure, GPS Network Unlocked GSM/UMTS/HSPA+ GSM/EDGE/GPRS (850, 900, 1800, 1900 MHz) 3G (850, 900, 1700, 1900, 2100 MHz) HSPA+ 42 Mbps Wireless Wireless display on a Miracast compatible HD TV Dual-band Wi-Fi (802.11 b/g/n) Bluetooth NFC (Android Beam) Power Wireless charging (use any Qi-compatible charger) 2,100 mAH Li-polymer battery Standby: up to 250 hours Talk time: up to 10 hours Music playback: up to 40 hours Video playback: up to 8 hours Web browsing: up to 7 hours OS Android Jelly Bean (4.2) Image via Engadget</Content></Article>