<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Hired Now Helps Tech Companies Find Executives</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/08/07/hired-engineering-management/</Url><Content>Hired, a startup working to make recruiting more efficient, has expanded to include a category for VPs of engineering and chief technical officers (CTOs). Engineering Management is now the company’s fifth vertical. Mickiewicz notes that while the new category will naturally be smaller than the original engineering vertical, it is a very profitable and important addition, as many companies look to expensive executive search firms when hiring for these positions. The startup, formerly known as DeveloperAuction, has been scaling as it fills its own internal hiring needs. CEO Matt Mickiewicz tells me internal needs drove the decision for Hired to launch UX/UI Designer, Data Scientist, and Product Manager verticals, and that Hired brought on employees in all three categories off its own platform. Just months after raising its $15 million Series A round, Hired seems to be growing at a healthy rate. Mickiewicz says the company currently has an eight-figure revenue run rate, and he notes that July 2014 revenue was triple January 2014’s revenue, when the company close the Series A. Hired, which has a little under 50 employees, currently has offices in San Francisco, New York, and Los Angeles. Mickiewicz says Hired plans to open offices in Seattle, Boston, and London by early 2015. In addition to expanding geographically, Mickiewicz says the company is looking a few years down the road at the non-tech hiring landscape. He specifically points to recruiting for the legal and finance sectors as potentially massive, profitable segments that “are really messy and broken.” This expansion beyond tech is where Hired could really get interesting. An undergrad at Stanford emailed me a few days ago explaining how working in investment banking for a summer led her to change paths and learn to code; she specifically mentioned Hired, noting that she wished the recruiting process for non-technical jobs was better. If Hired can keep growing its reach within technical recruiting while expanding to non-technical fields in the coming years, it could dramatically change the way companies recruit and hire talented people.</Content></Article>