<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>It’s Open Season For Spring 2015 Accelerator Programs</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2015/02/03/its-open-season-for-spring-2015-accelerator-programs/</Url><Content>Deadlines are looming for the over 400 accelerator programs revving up their spring and summer programs, so now’s the time to send in those applications. Budding entrepreneurs should be on the lookout for new programs from accelerators focused on transportation, robotics, eye care, and medical devices. Over 400 accelerator programs are listed in CrunchBase, and right now some of our favorites are revving up for their Spring and Summer batches. With deadlines quickly approaching, it’s time to send in those applications. Techstars is kicking off four programs this year, including one in Detroit with a focus on building transportation tech in the Motor City. Industry giants Ford, Magna International and Verizon Telematics have partnered with Detroit-based venture firms Fontinalis Partners, Detroit Venture Partners and Renaissance Venture Capital to fund the program. Techstars is also powering the Qualcomm Robotics Accelerator, designed to accelerate the next generation of smart machines that combine mechanics and intelligent controls, computer vision, sensors, navigation, and wireless communication. 2014 saw the rise of health and fitness startups and 2015 is maintaining the trend. Wellness Accelerator is an Italian based program seeking European startups in the fitness sector focused in wearable devices, platform, and big data. EyeFocus Accelerator, sponsored by Bayer HealthCare &amp; Carl Zeiss, is looking to disrupt eye care for the over 280 million people who are visually impaired and 39 million who are totally blind. EyeFocus is looking for startups producing products for preventing, curing and living with eye disease and blindness. ZeroTo510 Medical Device Accelerator focuses on leveraging the strength of the Memphis area, medical device research and manufacturing. The program enables startups to achieve the Food and Drug Administration’s 510(k) pre-market notification filing. Social impact accelerators are also riding the entrepreneurial tide. The Point of Light Civic Accelerator is focused on civic ventures for profit and nonprofit startups that include people as part of the solution to critical social problems. This year, the accelerator is partnering with the PWC Charitable Foundation, to tackle the familiar challenge — leveling the playing field for girls and women in tech.  Check out the full list of upcoming deadlines below: February: EyeFocus Accelerator -Berlin, Germany (2/15) 500 Startups -Mountain View, CA (2/20) Qualcomm Robotics Accelerator – San Diego, CA (2/22) Wellness Accelerator -Venice, Italy (2/28) March: Cylon Accelerator -London, U.K. (3/2) The Points of Light Civic Accelerator- Atlanta, GA (3/7) TechStars Boston- Boston, MA (3/15) TechStars Berlin- Berlin, Germany (3/15) TechStars Mobility- Detroit, MI (3/15) TechStars Boulder- Boulder, CO (3/15) ZeroTo510- Memphis, TN (3/16) AngelCube- Melbourne, Australia (3/23)</Content></Article>