<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>I’m Going To Interview Vine Co-Founder And GM Colin Kroll At Disrupt NY  And Then Vine It</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/14/im-going-to-interview-vine-co-founder-and-gm-colin-kroll-at-disrupt-ny-and-then-vine-it/</Url><Content>It’s been just over a year since Vine launched into the world, catapulted by parent company Twitter to bring mobile video creation to the masses. A lot has happened in that year, including the launch of Instagram video, Twitter’s IPO, and the explosion of mobile video apps. So what does Vine co-founder and GM Colin Kroll have to say about all this? Luckily, we’re about to find out. At Disrupt NY in early May, I’ll be hopping onstage with the Vine boss for a solid 20 minutes to discuss competition, monetization plans, the company’s relationship to Twitter, and the incredible acquisition story that started it all. And if time and Twitter permit, we might even delve into the porn scandals that littered the app’s history since launch. (You guys know how I love a good sex scandal.) Kroll started his career as a software engineer at Right Media, which was acquired by Yahoo in 2006. From then until 2011, Kroll led the engineering team in Yahoo’s search and advertising tech group before joining Jetsetter as VP of Product. He was then promoted to CTO just before leaving to start Vine in 2012 with co-founders Dominik Hofmann and Rus Yusopov. Before ever launching, Vine was bought out by Twitter and launched in January of 2013 as a video-flavored answer to Facebook’s Instagram. So far, competition has been heated in the space, not only with Instagram but with the many new entrants in the social mobile video vertical. In other words, there’s quite a bit to discuss. I’m stoked to be hosting Colin Kroll this year at Disrupt, and hopefully you’re just as excited as I am. Tickets are currently available for Disrupt NY. There are also numerous opportunities for startups to exhibit, sponsor and pitch at Disrupt. Our sponsors help make Disrupt happen. If you are interested in learning more about sponsorship opportunities, please contact our sponsorship team at sponsors@techcrunch.com</Content></Article>