<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>LinkedIn-Owned SlideShare Gets Its First iOS App</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/10/02/linkedin-owned-slideshare-gets-its-first-ios-app/</Url><Content>Better late than never? LinkedIn this morning announced it has at last rolled out the first-ever iOS app for SlideShare, the presentation and content-sharing platform it acquired back in 2012. The new app was built using Swift and is optimized to work on the iPhone 6 and 6 Plus, offering a modern, clean layout to browse and search through the presentations hosted on SlideShare’s service. SlideShare’s app also makes engaging with its content a more social experience, allowing you to like and share the presentations you come across, and follow the categories you care about. Users have their own profiles on the app, where you’re able to see all the presentations you’ve liked, uploaded and saved. And you can view presentations from your friends and professional network, tying LinkedIn’s social graph into SlideShare more directly, so you can see what’s popular within your own group. You’ll also be notified when someone in your network uploads something new, LinkedIn notes, and iPhone 6 and 6 Plus users will receive two customized “SlideShares of the Day” that regularly refresh in the Today section of your Notification Center – in other words, a widget that takes advantage of new features in iOS 8. Content from SlideShare can be downloaded for offline access, and the iOS app offers a full-screen landscape mode for better viewing. The company says it now has 15 million presentations available across categories including Technology, Business, Education, News &amp; Politics, Design, Marketing, Finance and Entertainment. Its website sees 60 million unique visitors per month and has more than 12 million uploads. This is not SlideShare’s first attempt at mobile, however. The company actually went Android-first. That version has now also been updated with the new features and is live on Google Play. Meanwhile, the iOS app is free here on iTunes.</Content></Article>