<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Live From Samsung’s CES 2015 Press Conference</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2015/01/05/live-from-samsungs-ces-2015-press-conference/</Url><Content>Phones! TVs! Washing machines! Fridges! Tablets, probably! Samsung makes everything, and CES is the South Korean company’s version of Christmas morning. That said, we have an excessive team of TechCrunchers covering the event, complete with the very live blog you’re reading right now. We’ll show you the phones, the TVs, the washing machines and driers and fridges and even the relatively crappy tablets. And beyond the products themselves, we’ll be providing live commentary on Samsung’s theatrics during the show, as the company has gotten more and more bold in their live press conferences over the years. So sit back, relax, and get ready for some Samsung. Some ‘sung. Whatever. Alex Wilhelm January 5, 20152:50 pm We’re all done here, and we sincerely thank you for bearing with us through this impossible Wifi connection. More coverage to follow. Bye, guys!  Alex Wilhelm January 5, 20152:49 pm And last but not least: Samsung PowerBot robotic vacuum offers 60x more suction power than traditional robotic vacuums, and lets you use a remote to map out your house and command the robot to clean a certain mess.  Alex Wilhelm January 5, 20152:48 pm New washing machine uses Super Speed to lower washing a load down to 36 minutes.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:48 pm Alex Wilhelm January 5, 20152:48 pm Home appliances stuff real quick: Dual door takes the Flex duo oven (cooking at two different temps) to a new level with TWO DOORS! Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:48 pm Samsung is building a roomba-style robot vacuum that lets you point a remote  control beam to tell the vacuum where to go Romain Dillet January 5, 20152:44 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:44 pm They’re also releasing a Chef Collection Tablet that comes with the app pre-loaded, as well as a cute little wooden stand so you can prop that bad boy up in the kitchen.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:42 pm Chef Collection app was just introduced. It lets chefs walk you through various recipes.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:41 pm Yes I love it when Greg lies!  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:41 pm A few chefs have come on stage to talk about how they collaborated on design.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:40 pm i lied! here you go: Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:39 pm That said, the new Chef Collection looks SICK. Like kitchen appliances from the future.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:39 pm my wifi tanked for a second. sorry guys, no pics of refrigerators for you! Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:39 pm Now we’re watching a video of Club des Chefs. Again… ?? Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:38 pm They’ve put a kitchen model up on stage, with a washing machine, oven, microwave and fridge.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:38 pm We’re watching a video of people cooking. ??  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:37 pm He’s going over 2014’s appliances sales. He says they’re up 10 percent in sales in home appliances.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:36 pm John Herrington, SVP of Samsung Electronics America is now on stage.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:36 pm He just stepped off stage and said thank you. Not sure what will happen next.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:35 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:35 pm Milk Music is coming to the Multi-Room app so that users can play the content they like on Milk using Samsung’s connected home tech.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:35 pm It’s a omni-directional speaker that kinda looks like a turret from portal Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:34 pm Samsung introduces the omni-directional sound experience. the Wam7500 &amp; 6500 projects sound in all directions using “ring radiator technology.”  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:33 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:32 pm They have a brand new Samsung Audio Lab, and they’re showing a video about it.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:32 pm We’re moving from what you see to what you hear. Audio products.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:31 pm Tizen is taking advantage of the second screen trend by sending content to your tablet or smartphone as you watch sports, such as replays, stats, etc.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:30 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:30 pm Tizen uses Quick Connect to let you throw content from TV to phone, or vice versa.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:29 pm All Samsung Smart TVs, starting this year, will be powered by the Tizen operating system, says Won-Jin Lee.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:29 pm The pedestal (see top): Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:28 pm That’s why it comes with a special pedestal that props it up, and controls the TV so that it faces the viewer as soon as it’s turned on. Pretty cool.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:28 pm Curved TV is “sculptural”.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:27 pm Or, if you do need an introduction: he’s the chief creative officer at jawbone, designer of the one-laptop-per-child laptop, Ouya, and a ton of other hardware. He’s designed for  herman miller, puma, GE, and, of course, Samsung. Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:25 pm Yay another guest! Yves Behar, who really doesn’t need any introduction. Incredible designer.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:25 pm Now we’re talking about the design of the S UHD TVs… the new chamfer bezel “looks stylish from any angle.”  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:24 pm It’s still unclear, spec-wise, how S UHD is different from UHD. “It’s The BEST picture technology, with the best content, thanks to the UHD Alliance.”  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:23 pm Nakamura totally loves S UHD. We’re shocked.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:22 pm They’re using “S” the same way they did with the Galaxy S. “S” stands for [superb, or slick, or some other good adjective that starts with “S” here]. Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:22 pm These guest appearances are so awkward. I love it.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:21 pm “Color is at the heart of this,” so Samsung is bringing up Stephen Nakamura who is a digital colorist.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:21 pm no word on what signifies “traditional.”  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:21 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:20 pm 64x the color expression of traditional tv’s… Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:20 pm He introduced a brand new TV that features S UHD… I think the S is for Samsung.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:20 pm I’m guessing Samsung. Or Super. Or Spaghetti. Probably Samsung. Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:19 pm Now we’re back with Stinziano: he’s introducing something called S UHD. There’s a TV that looks like it’s exploding or being struck with lightning. Still no word on what the “S” stands for.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:18 pm “The space is evolving rapidly, so the UHD Alliance is a huge step forward for the industry. Bring home the premium experience that only true UHD offers.” Seems to be taking a shot at Sony’s UHD.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:17 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:17 pm Mike Dunn, President of Home Entertainment at 20th Century Fox is on stage. “Focused on breaking down barriers to give the user a better experience.”  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:16 pm We’re bringing together a UHD ecosystem by bringing together DirectTV, Dolby Vision, Netflix, Panasonic, Sharp, technicolor, Disney, 20th Century Fox and Warner Brothers as part of the UHD Alliance, a newly formed group.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:15 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:15 pm He’s talking about how Samsung is the TV market leader because “people want to own a Samsung.”  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:14 pm Joe Stinziano, EVP of Samsung Electronics America, is on stage.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:14 pm David’s gone, and now we’re heading into some more announcements. We’ve heard there is no new phone to be unveiled, but maybe that was planted to throw us off the scent.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:13 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:13 pm NBA will also be a partner for Milk VR, giving users access to exclusive content from their favorite teams and players. Ideally.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:12 pm Relatively awkward celebrity appearance, but Walking Dead fans should be excited that walkers may come to VR.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:12 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:12 pm The producer of the Walking Dead is talking about how they’ll be using Milk VR to “push the boundaries of story telling”  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:11 pm Samsung is also introducing Milk VR, which lets brands create content that takes advantage of the Samsung Gear VR, a VR headset that uses the Galaxy Note as a display/power source.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:10 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:10 pm Milk Music will also be hitting up a PC near you in 2015.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:10 pm Milk Music and Milk Video: headed to Samsung Smart TVs.  Greg Kumparak January 5, 20152:09 pm Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:08 pm Moving on to the really juice stuff, semiconductor and storage space. Introduces Samsung portable SSD TI. smaller than a business card and holds up to 1TB of content.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:07 pm “See how we’ll unlock the power of your digital technology.”  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:06 pm Samsung’s focus is to pair great technology with content and services. Starts with IoT.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:05 pm Now talking about appliances, wearables and smartphones. Generally just hearing a lot of marketing speak right now.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:04 pm Expects big things for UHD in the next year.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:04 pm Says they have 60 percent of the UHD market. Up 5 percent from last year.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:03 pm “As a leader we understand the responsibility of creating new markets. We do this in three ways: 1. largest UHD lineup. 2. large UHD library on Samsung TVs. 3. Distribution through 8,000 Samsung retail experiences.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:02 pm Tim Baxter is on stage: We want to make it possible for people to live their passions. Make these passions come to life. This is what drove our innovation. Stuff like that.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20152:01 pm Samsung’s tag line is “Creating Possibilities: Shaping The Future” … JIC you were wondering.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20151:57 pm We’re trying to get you images ASAP but Samsung’s craptastic Wifi offerings here aren’t helping. Luckily the iPhone lets you tether! Hold tight.  Jordan Crook January 5, 20151:41 pm We’re here, and the room is slowly filling up. Should take a while, as the line trailed around many a corners. </Content></Article>