<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Manila-Based Altitude Games Raises $275 000 To Develop Midcore Titles</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/06/altitude-games/</Url><Content>Altitude Games, a Manila-based mobile game studio, has raised $275,000 in seed funding from investors Nix Nolledo, Level Up! Games co-founder Philip Cahiwat, an undisclosed angel investor, and members of its founding team. The startup will use the capital to “jumpstart its creation of original intellectual property in the midcore game space.” Altitude Games plans to announce its first title in May during Casual Connect Asia, an annual industry event in Singapore. In a statement, CEO Gabby Dizon says Altitude Games’ goal is to help establish the Southeast Asian gaming industry’s reputation for innovation. “Southeast Asian has previously been known as a great place to outsource game development, but we’re 100% focused on creating original intellectual property for mobile games. We want to combine midcore themes and casual accessibility to make games that are easy to pick up but contain deep gameplay that you can enjoy with your friends,” he said. Altitude Games’ founding team have been friends for more than 10 years and all have worked at leading Southeast Asian game developers. Dizon was previously senior producer at Singapore-based Boomzap Entertainment, one of Southeast Asia’s largest casual game developers, where he led business development and production. Before joining Boomzap, Dizon was CEO of Flipside Games and also served as president of the Game Developers Association of the Philippines. The rest of the team includes Luna Cruz, who was formerly senior designer at Boomzap, where she was the lead designer on Awakening: The Dreamless Castle. That game turned into one of publisher Big Fish Games’ top franchises and now includes six titles. Cruz also helped develop other Boomzap franchises like the Dana Knightstone and Otherworld series. Other Altitude Games founders include: Paul Gadi, former production lead at Gameloft Philippines and CTO at Anino Mobile; Marc Polican, former lead programmer at Boomzap and Gameloft Philippines; and Chester Ocampo, former art director at Imaginary Friends Studio.</Content></Article>