<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Mary Meeker’s 2011 Presentation On Internet Trends [Slides]</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2011/10/18/mary-meekers-2011-presentation-on-internet-trends-slides/</Url><Content>Kleiner Perkins partner and former Morgan Stanley analyst Mary Meeker is about to take the stage here at Web 2.0 Summit to present on Internet trends, as she does every year. I’ll be writing this up live, so keep refreshing. For now, you can flip through the slides above and take a gander at her 12 trend topics below. View this document on Scribd 1. Globality – We Aren’t In Kansas Anymore… Meeker revealed that 81% of users of the top ten global internet properties are outside the USA, which makes global markets a force to be reckoned with. 2. Mobile – Early Innings Growth, Still… iPhones, iPods and iPads have revolutionized the market. But Android tablets and phones, at a different price point, are not to be underestimated. 3. User Interface – Text/Graphical/ Touch / Sound / Move “Sound is going to be bigger than video. Record is the new Qwerty,” say SoundCloud CEO Alexander Ljung. 4. Commerce – Fast / Easy / Fun / Savings = More Important Than Ever… The ability to click and buy on a mobile device is making a huge difference in mobile commerce. “It’s now an expectation that if you see it on your screen, you can click and buy it,” says Meeker. 5. Advertising – Lookin’ Good… Look at Google’s click growth for an indicator of advertising health: 23% of clicks on ads is a good sign Meeker says. 6. Content Creation – Changed Forever Meeker refers to Joanne Bradford from DemandMedia doing a better job at talking about content creation. 7. Technology / Mobile Leadership – Americans Should Be Proud 64% of smartphones have U.S.A. OSes (iOS, Android, Windows Phone) versus 5% 5 years ago. 8. Mega-Trend of 21st Century = Empowerment of People via Connected Mobile Devices “The ability to get realtime fast and broad information flow is only going to get greater,” says Meeker. 9. Authentic Identity – The Good / Bad / Ugly. But Mostly Good? “One of the biggest topics of the next ten years,” Meeker says. 10. Economy – Lots of Uncertainty Despite lots of indicators of uncertainty, “We’ve had a good two weeks.” 11. USA Inc. – Pay Attention! The US ranks 10th on a list of country by debt. Greece, by comparison, ranks number 3.</Content></Article>