<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Mary Meeker On Ten Questions Internet Execs Should Ask And Answer</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2010/11/16/ten-questions-internet-execs-should-ask-and-answer/</Url><Content>View this document on Scribd Morgan Stanley analyst Mary Meeker has taken the stage here at Web 2.0 Summit to present on Internet trends and we’ve got a preview of the slides for her “Ten Questions Internet Execs Should Ask And Answer” presentation. Meeker’s ten questions are: 1. Globality — Do you know which players in which countries do what you do better (or at least differently) than you do? Do you study / implement it? 2. Mobile — Ramping faster than any ‘new new thing’ – is your business leading or lagging? 3. Social Ecosystems — Would you rather be Apple, Google or…Facebook? Will their future directions help / hurt your business? 4. Advertising – Ripe for innovation – will your business benefit? 5. Commerce — Products must be fast + easy + fun. Do humans want everything to be like a game? 6. Media — What does the extraordinary ramp in on-demand video usage mean for your business? 7. Internet Company Leadership Evolution — Shocking changes over just 6 years… are you prepared for next half decade of change? 8. Steve Jobs — What’s his ‘secret sauce?’ Does your company have it? 9. Ferocious Pace of Change – What’s Next in Tech? — When do consumers / enterprises &amp; incumbents / attackers need you? 10. Closing Thoughts – Large companies do not typically support rapid growth rates of the magnitude that follow..will these trends continue? Meeker begun the presentation by pointing out that the 5 markets to watch for mobile in 2011 will be the US, Japan, Indonesia, China and Brazil. Feeling positive about the state of the online advertising industry, Meeker also points out that we spend 28% of our time on the internet, but only 13% of advertising is there, revealing an untapped $50 billion opportunity in online ads (!). Meeker says she’s clicked on more online ads in the past six months than she has in the past 15 years. We’re seeing unusually high levels of innovation according to Meeker, most prominent examples being the iPad, the iPhone and Facebook. There is actually a whole slide on Steve Jobs, who according to Larry Ellison has “the mind of an engineer and the heart of an artist.” Overall Internet companies have seen a strong third quarter and are poised for a strong fourth, primarily led by high level growth companies like Apple, Google and Amazon.</Content></Article>