<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Meet The Pitch-Off Winners Of The Austin And Seattle Meetups</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/15/meet-the-pitch-off-winners-of-the-austin-and-seattle-meetups/</Url><Content>Advertisement After a long, exhilarating week hunting down the coolest new startups in Austin and Seattle, I’m proud to announce the winners of our recent TechCrunch Pitch-offs. They triumphed through a sixty-second pitch, stood up against a barrage of questions from local venture capitalists and TechCrunch editors, and most importantly, impressed hundreds of potential users in the audience. So without any further ado, meet the winners: Austin: First place – TeVido Biodevices TeVido BioDevices is an early-stage life sciences/biotech company using 3D bio-printing of a woman’s own living cells to build custom grafts for breast cancer reconstruction. Their first product is targeted to improve nipple reconstruction and later fill lumpectomies. Second place – Peep Related Videos Play Video MaxField Powers Magnetic Receptive Walls 5:41 Play Video 23andMe Opens Its API to Further Personalize Healthcare Play Video Secret’s CEO Discusses Cyberbullying Policy More Related Videos Peep is a piece of hardware that attaches to your door’s peephole. By connecting to an app on your smartphone, you can see who’s at your front door whether your home or not, and people can even leave in-person voicemails when you miss them. Audience Choice – Stretch Recipes Stretch is a life-made-easy app that helps people pair their budget with food dislikes to make purchasing decisions at the grocery store. Stretch provides nutritional chef recipes while letting users earn points towards coupons. Seattle: First place – EssayMentors EssayMentors is an online and/or in-person mentoring program that helps teenagers write their college application essays. The company partners with schools and non-profits to provide tools to students. CrunchBase TechCrunch Founded 2005     Overview TechCrunch is a leading technology media property, dedicated to obsessively profiling startups, reviewing new Internet products, and breaking tech news. Founded in June 2005, TechCrunch and its network of websites now reach over 12 million unique visitors and draw more than 37 million page views per month. The TechCrunch community includes more than 2 million friends and followers on Twitter, Facebook, … Location San Francisco, California Categories News, Internet, Events, Media Website http://techcrunch.com Full profile for TechCrunch Second place – VetCommander VetCommander is a platform that connects veterans with the right job. The service offers the chance to create an interactive video resume, ensuring the vet always gets feedback (whether the interviewer responds or not) and offering a better way for the employer to get to know them. Audience Choice – Canary Canary is an on-demand mobile marijuana delivery service aimed toward medical card holders in Seattle and Denver. The app lets you filter by strain or dispensary and promises delivery within an hour. The company hires medical card-holding, knowledgable couriers to ensure the end user gets a great experience. All of these winners will attend TechCrunch Disrupt in San Francisco this fall, with the first place companies getting a table in Startup Alley. We had a blast in Austin and Seattle and thank both cities for welcoming us. Until next time, take a look at the pictures. 0 SHARES 0 Share 0 Tweet 0 Share 0 0 0 0</Content></Article>