<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>MetroPCS launches LTE in San Francisco  still only one compatible featurephone</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2010/12/01/metropcs-launches-lte-in-san-francisco-still-only-one-compatible-featurephone/</Url><Content>If you’re the type of person that craves high download speeds, but doesn’t go for the whole “smartphone” thing (plus you live in SF), then — as strange as it may sound — MetroPCS have you covered. Today MetroPCS launched their LTE network in San Francisco, and — just like before — are only offering the one device to use on it. Namely, the Samsung Craft. Yup, it’s a featurephone. I dunno, maybe you want it so you can be ironic or something. If you find the prospect of owning an LTE phone that doesn’t really take advantage of LTE interesting, you can scoop up the Samsung Craft for $299 contract-free, and can expect to pay $55-$60 a month in access fees, depending on if you want access to their video-on-demand service or not. With Verizon announcing the launch of their LTE network today, maybe we can hope that MetroPCS follow up with a smartphone sometime soon, or at the very least a USB modem. MetroPCS Launches 4G LTE Network in San Francisco Metropolitan Area Experience Unlimited 4G LTE Mobile Broadband with the Entertainment-Rich Samsung CraftTM DALLAS – (Dec. 1, 2010) – MetroPCS Communications Inc. (NYSE: PCS) today launched unlimited, no annual contract 4G LTE services in the San Francisco metropolitan area starting at $55 per month including taxes and regulatory fees. Accessible on the world’s first commercially available 4G LTE handset, the Samsung CraftTM, MetroPCS’ 4G LTE network allows consumers to do more with unlimited talk, text and enhanced entertainment and web browsing features. “We can’t add hours to the day, but we can help consumers do more in the hours they have. With easy access to social networks and enhanced web browsing capabilities, our customers can stay on top of the latest news, access their favorite content through MetroSTUDIOSM, and keep up with friends, family and colleagues,” said Roger D. Linquist, president, CEO and chairman of MetroPCS. “As the only no annual contract, pay-in-advance service provider offering 4G LTE services, MetroPCS continues to deliver the innovative, flexible and affordable services our customers rely on.” The Samsung Craft is available in-store in all MetroPCS markets or online for $299 plus tax after the $50 instant rebate, while supplies last. Customers can take advantage of all MetroPCS 4G LTE has to offer with the Samsung Craft, including: * MetroSTUDIO, powered by RealNetworks, available on the $60 service plan, delivers full-track downloads, ringtones and ring-back tones, as well as premium video content from NBC Universal, Black Entertainment Television (BET) and Univision, available on-demand from one easy-to-use application. * A social networking and instant messaging application which harnesses notifications, friends and content from Facebook, MySpace and Twitter and AIM, MSN and Yahoo! IM clients into a single interface that’s accessible with one click. * Upgraded MetroNavigator® feature includes new voice-activated GPS and turn-by-turn directions. The Samsung Craft features a brilliant 3.3 inch AMOLED (active-matrix organic light-emitting diode) screen for a better video experience, and comes with a 2GB MicroSD card pre-loaded with Paramount Pictures’ hit movie “Star Trek – The Future Begins.” The Samsung Craft also contains a combination touch screen, slide-out QWERTY keyboard, Samsung’s TouchWizTM user interface to surf and text message, 3.2 megapixel camera with flash, camcorder and is Wi-Fi capable. With today’s launch in the San Francisco metropolitan area, MetroPCS now provides 4G LTE services in six metropolitan areas, including Dallas-Fort Worth, Detroit, Las Vegas, Los Angeles and Philadelphia. MetroPCS has plans to expand its 4G services into more major metropolitan areas later this year and into early 2011, including Atlanta, Boston, Jacksonville, Miami, New York, Orlando, Sacramento and Tampa. For more information, please visit: Details on rate plans and service features: http://www.metropcs.com/plans Press resources: http://www.metropcs.com/presscenter Follow MetroPCS on Twitter: http://www.twitter.com/metropcs Become a fan of MetroPCS on Facebook: http://www.facebook.com/metropcs View MetroPCS’ latest videos: http://www.YouTube.com/metropcs About MetroPCS Communications, Inc. Dallas-based MetroPCS Communications, Inc. (NYSE: PCS) is a provider of unlimited wireless communications service for a flat-rate with no annual contract. MetroPCS is the fifth largest facilities-based wireless carrier in the United States based on number of subscribers served. With Metro USASM, MetroPCS customers can use their services in areas throughout the United States covering a population of over 280 million people. As of September 30, 2010, MetroPCS had approximately 7.9 million subscribers. For more information please visit http://www.metropcs.com. Forward-Looking Statements Except for the historical information contained herein, this press release contains forward-looking statements as defined within Section 27A of the Securities Act of 1933, as amended, and Section 21E of the Securities and Exchange Act of 1934, as amended. These statements, including those pertaining to 4G LTE Services and networks, availability of service and handsets and launch dates of future LTE networks, are subject to risks and uncertainties and are based upon MetroPCS management’s experience in the industry, as well as its perceptions of historical trends, current conditions, expected future developments and other factors management believes are appropriate under the circumstances as of the date of this press release unless specified as of some earlier date. Actual financial results, performance or results of operations may differ materially from forward-looking statement expressed in this presentation. MetroPCS related brands, product names, company names, trademarks, service marks, images, symbols, copyrighted material, and other intellectual property are the exclusive properties of MetroPCS Wireless, Inc. and its subsidiaries, parent companies, and affiliates. Copyright ©2010 MetroPCS Wireless, Inc. All rights reserved. Other brands, product names, company names, trademark and service marks are the property of their respective owners. [via Engadget]</Content></Article>