<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Microsoft and Oracle Team Up To Bring Java  Oracle Database  Linux and WebLogic Server To Azure And Windows Server</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2013/06/24/microsoft-and-oracle-team-up-to-bring-java-oracle-database-linux-and-weblogic-server-to-azure-and-windows-server/</Url><Content>Ahead of their joint press conference later today, Microsoft and Oracle announced a new partnership that will bring a number of Oracle products to Windows Server and the company’s Azure cloud computing platform. These Oracle products include Java, Oracle Database and Oracle WebLogic Server. Starting today, Oracle customers can run supported Oracle software on Windows Server Hyper-V and in Windows Azure. Oracle also now provides license mobility for customers who want to run its software on Azure and bring Oracle Linux to Azure. Microsoft, on the other hand, will offer Java in Windows Azure and will soon add Infrastructure Services instances with configurations for Oracle Java, Oracle Database and WebLogic Server to the Windows Azure image gallery. As Microsoft’s Satya Nadella, Microsoft’s president of its server and tools business notes in the company’s announcement today, he believes that “this partnership will help customers embrace cloud computing by improving flexibility and choice while also preserving the first-class support that these workloads demand.” Oracle president Mark Hurd echoes this statement and also notes that Oracle is “committed to providing greater choice and flexibility to customers by providing multiple deployment options for our software, including on-premises, as well as public, private, and hybrid clouds. This collaboration with Microsoft extends our partnership and is important for the benefit of our customers.” It’s worth noting that Amazon Web Services also offers a number of Oracle enterprise solutions for its customers. The partnership with Microsoft, however, seems to go a bit beyond this and, for the most part, covers a different set of services.</Content></Article>