<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Motorola Officially Unveils The Droid RAZR HD And Droid RAZR MAXX HD</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2012/09/05/motorola-officially-unveils-the-droid-razr-hd-and-droid-razr-maxx-hd/</Url><Content>The Droid Razr HD has been spinning its way around the rumor mill for quite some time. But today, in rainy New York city at Gotham Hall, Motorola is officially unleashing the device on the world. Not only that, the RAZR MAXX HD (what a mouthful) was also unveiled for anyone who needs even more battery life. The big thing (literally) we’re looking at a 4.7-inch Super AMOLED HD display, something that Motorola’s Rick Osterloh is currently on stage talking up. Motorola’s engineers worked to stretch the display to the device’s corners without actually increasing the device’s size. As expected, the RAZR HD also features a 1.5GHz dual-core processor (the same Snapdragon chip seen in the smaller RAZR M). Sadly, there’s no Jelly Bean to be found just yet — Woodside announced that the devices revealed today would get that much-vaunted update shortly. The real story, however, is in the battery. Sure, the display is beautiful, and Motorola has been upping its screen game for the past few generations, but where Moto really made a splash was with the Droid Razr Maxx, which held a 3300mAh battery. For a reference point, that’s more than double the current iPhone battery. Today, with the announcement of the Droid Razr HD, we’re also seeing that massive battery, which should last you through at least about 16 straight hours. It’s part of a bigger focus of Motorola’s on power management going forward, a stance espoused by Motorola Mobility CEO Dennis Woodside. Naturally, the heftier RAZR MAXX HD packs the same 3300 mAh battery as seen in the original RAZR MAXX, which equates to something like 21 hours of straight usage before having to recharge. Sadly, there’s no Jelly Bean to be found just yet — Woodside announced that the devices revealed today would get that much-vaunted update shortly. Motorola hasn’t yet disclosed a released for the two devices, though the company was quick to note that the device will launch before the holidays.</Content></Article>