<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Netflix Signs Multi-Year Licensing Agreement With Turner Broadcasting And Warner Bros  Television</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/14/netflix-signs-multi-year-licensing-agreement-with-turner-broadcasting-and-warner-bros-television/</Url><Content>Netflix isn’t all about movies, as you know. The company has been adding more television to its on-demand service and today announced multi-year licensing agreements with both Turner Broadcasting and Warner Bros. Television Group. The agreement includes episodes of shows from Cartoon Network, Warner Bros. Animation, Adult Swim, and the show Dallas from TNT. The deal, which will only make content available to U.S. Netflix subscribers, goes into effect on March 30. It’s important to note that Jeff Bewkes, CEO of Time Warner, hasn’t been a fan of Netflix in the past. Here’s what Ted Sarandos, Chief Content Officer of Netflix, had to say: We are delighted that Netflix will become the exclusive over-the-top streaming subscription destination for past seasons of favorite Cartoon Network and Adult Swim titles. We’re also thrilled to be able to offer the latest seasons of Dallas, one of the greatest all-time guilty pleasures. Here’s a full listing of the shows that will become available on Netflix via the deal: Cartoon Network: Adventure Time, Ben 10, Regular Show and Johnny Bravo Adult Swim: Robot Chicken, Aqua Teen Hunger Force, The Boondocks and Childrens Hospital Green Lantern from Warner Bros. will show up in the “Just For Kids” section of Netflix. As with any licensing deal like this, it’s probably a way to see how the companies involved can work together in a fluid way, which means that more titles could come in the near future. If this news doesn’t get you excited, then the recent “Arrested Development” update surely will. There are plenty of people who have ditched cable television to consume content through Netflix, Hulu Plus and other Internet-based services. These types of deals make that “cord cutting” decision much easier. [Photo credit: Flickr]</Content></Article>