<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Nominations For The 8th Annual Crunchies End Soon — Get Yours In Today </Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/12/02/crunchies-nominations-end-soon/</Url><Content>Facebook LinkedIn The Crunchies It’s that time of year again. The 8th Annual Crunchies Awards will soon be upon us, but if we’re going to give out any awards, we’re going to need your help. Each year, the Crunchies brings together the best and brightest from the startup ecosystem for a night of awards and schmoozing with their peers. As last year’s host John Oliver noted so astutely, the Crunchies are “like the Nobel Prizes being given out, if Nobel Prizes were given out in an atmosphere of high-school bitchiness.” Next February we hope to carry on that tradition with a new host — Silicon Valley’s hilarious T.J. Miller — who will be there to help us highlight all the best startups, founders, apps, and technologies over the past year, and probably make fun of those who don’t end up winning. But to do that, we’re accepting nominations from our readers to help narrow down the overwhelming list of candidates. Great news, right? But! Nominations end in just under 36 hours — at 11:59 p.m. PST on December 3, to be exact — so be sure to cast your vote for nominees and let us know who you think should be up for the awards. So anyway, get your nominations in. And get your tickets already. It’ll be February before you know it. Our list of categories and most recent winners is below: Best Technology Achievement (2013: bitcoin) Best On-Demand Service (2013: Airbnb) Best E-Commerce Application (2013: Wanelo) Best Mobile Application (2013: Snapchat) Fastest Rising Startup (2013: Upworthy) Best Health Startup (2013: One Medical) Best Design (2013: Pencil by FiftyThree) Best Bootstrapped Startup (2013: Imgur) Best Enterprise Startup (2013: Zendesk) Best International Startup (2013: Waze) Best Education Startup (2013: Duolingo) Best Hardware Startup (2013: Oculus VR) Can’t Stop, Won’t Stop (2013: Candy Crush Saga) Biggest Social Impact (2013: Edward Snowden’s NSA Revelations) Angel of the Year (2013: Chris Sacca) VC of the Year (2013: Peter Fenton, Benchmark) Founder of the Year (2013: Arash Ferdowsi &amp; Drew Houston, Dropbox) CEO of the Year (2013: Dick Costolo, Twitter) Best New Startup of 2014 (2013: Tinder) Best Overall Startup of 2014 (2013: Kickstarter)</Content></Article>