<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Oracle Buys Tekelec To Move Closer To Carriers And Their Overstretched Data Networks</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/25/oracle-buys-tekelec-to-move-closer-to-carriers-and-their-overstretched-data-networks/</Url><Content>Oracle continues on its acquisition trail to build out a more full-service operation targeting the carrier market. Today it announced that it would acquire Tekelec, a provider of network signaling, policy control, and subscriber data management solutions. It says it plans to integrate Tekelec’s solutions into its Communications portfolio, and specifically with products from Acme Packet, a business that specialises in so-called session border control solutions, to help transfer packets of data securely across IP networks. Oracle announced in February that it would buy Acme Packet for $2.1 billion but the deal has yet to complete. An Oracle spokesperson confirmed to TechCrunch directly that the finacial terms of the Tekelec deal are not being disclosed. Tekelec first started out as an old-school electronics company aimed at the aviation industry in Europe in 1961. In 1971 it got incorporated in the U.S., initially as a telecoms equipment provider for testing services. Prior to Oracle’s acquisition, it was owned by the Siris Capital Group, which took control of it in January 2012 for some $780 million. The company has moved with the times, and has specialities in IP services specifically around network signaling, policy control, and subscriber data management, three areas that carriers need to manage in data networks to balance user loads and keep services running smoothly. On the data management side, Tekelec’s services are important in helping to measure and meter how data is used, in both broadband and mobile networks. Those solutions are already in use by some 300 carriers in 100 countries — giving Oracle a channel to growing its own business connections with these same customers. “As connected devices and applications become ubiquitous, intelligent network and service control technologies are required to enable service providers to efficiently deploy all-IP networks, and deliver and monetize innovative communication services,” said Bhaskar Gorti, senior vice president and general manager, Oracle Communications, in a statement. “The combination of Oracle and Tekelec will provide service providers with the most complete solution to manage their businesses across customer engagement, business and network operations, service delivery and end user applications.” Tekelec, meanwhile highlights that the explosion of mobile services, along with always-connected apps, are having a particularly strong effect on the market. “In an increasingly mobile and social world, customer experience is about optimizing network performance and personalizing services based on what engages, moves, and inspires people,” said Ron de Lange, president and CEO, Tekelec, in a statement. “Together with Oracle, we expect to accelerate the pace of service innovation by helping service providers transform the way they manage and monetize the explosive growth in signaling and data traffic on their networks.” And, as a reader points out below, IP where Tekelec is concerned goes beyond Internet protocol: it also owns hundreds of patents and applications in the communications space. This is an area that Oracle has not hesitated to explore in the courtroom, and given the billion-dollar-plus sums involved in some patent battles, this could have bumped up the pricetag for Tekelec somewhat higher.</Content></Article>