<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Philips Announces Multi-Room Speakers That Connect To Spotify</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2015/01/05/philips-announces-multi-room-speakers-that-connect-to-spotify/</Url><Content>Don’t tell Taylor Swift! Philips has announced a set of speakers that connect directly to Spotify and allow you to move your queue to the speakers from your mobile device. The system also supports an adapter, pictured, that lets you use your own speakers to get some dulcet tones out of your Spotify queue. How does it work? Well, there’s a single button to bring up Spotify content. Press it and you get “warm, detailed sound” out of the $130 speakers. Quoth Philips: ￼ You’ve just walked in your front door and you’re listening to your favorite playlist. Simply press the Spotify button on the Philips Spotify multiroom speaker in your hallway and the music instantly picks up right where you left off – ensuring that you don’t miss a single note. You walk into your lounge and pick up your tablet, choosing a track that you’ve been looking forward to all day. Next, you press the Spotify button on the speaker in your lounge, which instantly takes over the tune from the speaker in the hallway. “Shake it off” indeed. LAS VEGAS – The Philips Spotify multiroom speakers are the first dedicated Philips audio solution for Spotify users. Incorporating Spotify Connect, controlling your music across your phone, tablet and speakers from the native Spotify app is effortless. You can place Philips Spotify multiroom speakers throughout your home and stream your music to every room at the same time: create a sound experience that’s as personal to you as the music you love. The speaker range consists of two models, both of which include a Spotify ‘one press play’ button, which you simply press once to start the music flowing. You’ve just walked in your front door and you’re listening to your favorite playlist. Simply press the Spotify button on the Philips Spotify multiroom speaker in your hallway and the music instantly picks up right where you left off – ensuring that you don’t miss a single note. You walk into your lounge and pick up your tablet, choosing a track that you’ve been looking forward to all day. Next, you press the Spotify button on the speaker in your lounge, which instantly takes over the tune from the speaker in the hallway, filling the room with warm, detailed sound. “With the Philips Spotify multiroom speakers, the dream of seamless, high-quality music streaming throughout your home is now within reach,” said Benjamin Ngo, Audio Business Line Leader at WOOX Innovation. “These products are an important part of our multiroom audio strategy, delivering great quality sound and a seamless user experience. Incorporating Spotify Connect, you won’t be disturbed by unstable connections when streaming music to the speakers. Incoming phone calls, loss of signal range, or watching a video won’t spoil the party: the music just keeps flowing.” “Before Spotify Connect, streaming music at home could be a frustrating experience with issues like audio quality and battery drainage getting in the way of enjoying your favorite music,” said Pascal de Mul, Global head of hardware partnerships at Spotify. “The Philips Spotify multiroom speakers deliver on the vision that we have for effortless, high-quality music streaming at home, leaving you to focus on enjoying the music.” The Philips Spotify multiroom speakers also come with a separate app that enables you to easily group multiple speakers into a single set. Just set this up once and you can then select the speaker group in the native Spotify app anytime you want. Ensuring advanced performance, the Philips Spotify multiroom speaker range includes technology from Frontier Silicon, a leading provider of technology solutions in connected audio. There are two models in the Philips Spotify multiroom speaker range. The SW700M includes two 2.5” full-range speaker drivers and two expanded bass ports to create a clear, natural sound. The SW750M incorporates two tweeters and two 3” full-range drivers to deliver detailed, powerful and room-filling sound. Both speakers can be used in combination across different rooms for a true multiroom experience. The Philips Spotify multiroom speakers will be available North America in Spring 2015. The SW700M model’s suggested retail is $129.99 and the larger SW750M suggested retail is $179.99. Spotify Multiroom Adapter Making it even easier to enjoy Spotify in any room is the new Philips Spotify Multiroom Adapter (SW100M). The Philips Spotify Multiroom Adapter allows you to use the Spotify app with almost any existing speaker with a simple Analog (RCA) or Digital (Coaxial and Optical) output connection. Once connected, users can access the Spotify App to browse and play music on the selected speaker. Similar to the Philips Spotify Multiroom speakers, the adapter offers many of the same benefits to users, such as playing a song wherever you left on your mobile, playing the song on multiple speakers and move the music from room to room. The Philips Spotify Multiroom Adapter allows you effortless to bring the wide selection of music Spotify has to offer into every room of the house. The SW100M will be available in North American in Spring 2015 with a suggested retail price of $99. ￼</Content></Article>