<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Quantcast Acquires Ad Personalization And Retargeting Company Struq</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/10/01/quantcast-acquires-struq/</Url><Content>Quantcast is announcing that it has acquired Struq, a London-based company that offers cross-device retargeting and personalization for advertisers. Quantcast may be best known for its data about Internet traffic, but it seems to have built a thriving ad business as well. The company’s announcement emphasizes the ways in which Struq technology can expand Quantcast’s ad platform, in part because Quantcast’s ad products and Struq’s have different targets: Quantcast focuses on helping businesses find new customers, while Struq’s technology helps those businesses reconnect with potential customers who have already shown an interest in their products. (Struq targets and personalizes the ads based on where someone is in the “conversion funnel.”) “Combining Quantcast’s unrivaled data about online user behavior with our ad personalization technology will lead to a deeper understanding of users and enable us to more effectively personalize an ad to them,” said Struq CEO and founder Sam Barnett in the acquisition release. The financial terms of the deal are not being disclosed, but the companies said they will combine offices in London, New York, San Francisco and Los Angeles, with the London office becoming Quantcast’s third “Engineering Hub.” I’ve emailed Quantcast for more details about the deal and will update if I hear back. Back in 2012, Struq raised an $8.5 million funding round from Reed Elsevier Ventures, Pentech Ventures, and Allen &amp; Company. Update: In response to my questions, CEO Konrad Feldman told me that the entire 50-person Struq team will be joining Quantcast, bringing its total headcount to nearly 600. He also said that there will be no interruption of service to existing Struq customers. “The work to integrate our products has already started and we’ll be iterating quickly so that our clients can quickly realize the benefits of our combined solutions,” Feldman added.</Content></Article>