<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>RadiumOne Buys Mobile Photo Sharing App Developer Focal Labs</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/14/radiumone-buys-mobile-photo-sharing-app-developer-focal-labs/</Url><Content>RadiumOne, an online ad network that aims to combine social and intent data to serve ads, has acquired Focal Labs, the developer of the photo sharing and geo location apps Clixtr and PicBounce, according to sources familiar with the matter. Clixtr, which launched at TechCrunch50, aims to turn smartphones into ‘social cameras’. The basic idea behind the service is that when you’re at an event, be it a birthday party at your home or at a massive rock concert, photos from multiple people attending could be turned into one single, centralized photo album. To make this work, even when pictures are taken by people you do not know, Clixtr uses location as the tying factor. The app essentially combines the capabilities of the iPhone’s camera and built-in GPS to geo-tag photos and determine when photos are being taken at the same location. Picbounce allows you to upload a photo from your iPhone to Facebook or Twitter and has been downloaded more than a million times. For background, RadiumOne mines social data and use this information to identify relevant consumers for brands. Through what founder Gurbaksh Chahal calls “social retargeting,” RadiumOne analyzes how users interact with one another on social networks to find the consumers that identify with a brand’s current customer base, and then serves advertisements to this audience across the company’s network of publishers. The company just raised $21 million in new funding at a $200 million valuation. It’s unclear how RadiumOne plans to use Focal Labs, Clixtr and PicBounce (another photo sharing app), but the company has been expanding to social, consumer-focused products as well. RadiumOne recently launched PingMe, a group messaging app. Clearly as Chahal has told us in the past, social sharing is a focal point (no pun intended) for the company and Focal Labs, which has an expertise in photo sharing apps, could help further this agenda.</Content></Article>