<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Remember To Vote For Crunchies Finalists </Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/01/17/remember-to-vote-for-crunchies-finalists/</Url><Content>Building a startup is hard. That’s why we celebrate the entrepreneurial spirit (and all the cool stuff you guys do) every year at our annual Crunchies awards show. But now we need your input. We’ve narrowed the field down to dozens of worthy competitors and we need to pick a winner. We do that by asking you to vote. Who will win Best Technology Achievement? Bitcoin or Node.js? Who is getting the trophy for Best Mobile App, Mailbox or Snapchat? Is Fitbit the best health startup? It’s all up to you. Get the word out. Vote for your own team. Vote for your favorite team. Make this a night to remember and make all that blood, sweat, and tears worth it. Vote for the Crunchies. The awards ceremony will take place on Monday, February 10, 2014, at Davies Symphony Hall in San Francisco, beginning at 7:30 p.m. Davies is an elegant venue that has hosted some of the greatest musical performances in SF history. We’re excited to hold the Crunchies here for yet another year. And then there’s the after party. As always there will be a hosted bar, hors d’oeuvres, interactive entertainment and other fun surprises including the chance to schmooze with the TC team at Davies. General admission tickets are now available and start at $80. It’s going to be a tight competition, so start voting now. There are 20 award categories that recognize the top accomplishments across a variety of fields and roles. Everyone is eligible and encouraged to vote. And we know you’re excited, but you may only vote once per day per award category until voting closes on Sunday, January 26, 2014, at 11:59 p.m. PST. Winners will be announced on Monday, February 10, 2014, at the 7th Annual Crunchies. See you there! Best Technology Achievement Apple A7 Processor (Related Posts) Bitcoin (Related Posts) node.js (Related Posts) Planet Labs low-cost satellites (Related Posts) Project Loon (Related Posts) Best Collaborative Consumption Service Airbnb (Related Posts) Crowdtilt (Related Posts) DogVacay (Related Posts) Homejoy (Related Posts) Lyft (Related Posts) Best E-Commerce Application BarkBox (Related Posts) Good Eggs (Related Posts) Polyvore (Related Posts) Warby Parker (Related Posts) Wanelo (Related Posts) Best Mobile Application Mailbox (Related Posts) Snapchat (Related Posts) Tinder (Related Posts) VSCO Cam WhatsApp (Related Posts) Fastest Rising Startup Lulu (Related Posts) QuizUp (Related Posts) Tinder (Related Posts) Upworthy (Related Posts) Whisper (Related Posts) Best Health Startup Fitbit (Related Posts) MyFitnessPal (Related Posts) One Medical Group (Related Posts) Oscar (Related Posts) Practice Fusion (Related Posts) Best Design Exposure by Elepath Nest Protect (Related Posts) Pencil by FiftyThree (Related Posts) Hi (Related Posts) Yahoo Weather (Related Posts) Best Bootstrapped Startup Grammarly Imgur (Related Posts) NerdWallet (Related Posts) SmugMug (Related Posts) TaskUs Sexiest Enterprise Startup Box (Related Posts) ClearSlide (Related Posts) New Relic (Related Posts) Optimizely (Related Posts) Zendesk (Related Posts) Best International Startup BlaBlaCar (Related Posts) Huddle (Related Posts) Supercell (Related Posts) Waze (Related Posts) Xiaomi (Related Posts) Best Education Startup Code.org (Related Posts) CreativeLIVE (Related Posts) Duolingo (Related Posts) Khan Academy (Related Posts) Treehouse (Related Posts) Best Hardware Startup 3D Robotics (Related Posts) Oculus VR (Related Posts) SmartThings (Related Posts) Sonos (Related Posts) Square (Related Posts) Can’t Stop, Won’t Stop Candy Crush Saga (Related Posts) Netflix (Related Posts) Tinder (Related Posts) Vibease (Related Posts) Vine (Related Posts) Biggest Social Impact Code.org (Related Posts) Crowdtilt (Related Posts) Edward Snowden’s NSA Revelations (Related Posts) StopWatching.Us (Related Posts) Watsi (Related Posts) Angel of the Year Steve Anderson (Related Posts) Michael Dearing (Related Posts) Keith Rabois (Related Posts) Naval Ravikant &amp; Babak Nivi (Related Posts) Chris Sacca (Related Posts) VC of the Year Peter Fenton (Benchmark) (Related Posts) Jim Goetz (Sequoia Capital) (Related Posts) Reid Hoffman (Greylock Partners) (Related Posts) Bill Maris (Google Ventures) (Related Posts) Bijan Sabet (Spark Capital) (Related Posts) Founder of the Year Drew Houston &amp; Arash Ferdowsi (Dropbox) (Related Posts) David Karp (Tumblr) (Related Posts) Aaron Levie (Box) (Related Posts) Matthew Prince, Michelle Zatlyn &amp; Lee Holloway (CloudFlare) (Related Posts) Deena Varshavskaya (Wanelo) (Related Posts) CEO of the Year Jeff Bezos (Amazon) (Related Posts) Dick Costolo (Twitter) (Related Posts) Travis Kalanick (Uber) (Related Posts) Marissa Mayer (Yahoo!) (Related Posts) Elon Musk (Tesla Motors &amp; SpaceX) (Related Posts) Best New Startup of 2013 Anki (Related Posts) Coinbase (Related Posts) Glow (Related Posts) Tinder (Related Posts) Whisper (Related Posts) Best Overall Startup of 2013 CloudFlare (Related Posts) Kickstarter (Related Posts) Snapchat (Related Posts) Twitter (Related Posts) Uber (Related Posts)</Content></Article>