<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Roomlia Takes On HotelTonight With Mobile Hotel Reservations App</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/08/25/roomlia-takes-on-hoteltonight-with-mobile-hotel-reservations-app/</Url><Content>Today Roomlia has launched into the App Store to provide the fastest hotel booking on mobile. Started by two former Expedia employees, Michael Reichartz and Jim Ferguson, Roomlia offers discounted hotel rooms up to seven days in advance with only a few clicks to complete booking. Unlike Expedia and its counterparts, Roomlia links you directly with your chosen hotel the moment you book, as opposed to negotiating rates and payments through the hotel site and the hotel itself. Roomlia links directly with hotels’ operations systems to make sure that the experience is super quick and painless. When you first log in, you’re given an extensive list of cities. You can choose one, or search for one that isn’t on the list, and you’re immediately shown a list of hotels with pictures, ratings, and average prices. Certain hotel rooms have extra deep discounts, which is displayed with a red flag on the listing. These only last a limited time. Users can put in their hotel dates on the bottom using a calendar or a slider to show the number of nights desired. Roomlia users have the opportunity to book a stay as long as five nights. HotelTonight, on the other hand, only gets you discounts on the day of booking. Once you choose a hotel, you can simply swipe to the left to book, sending you directly into contact with the hotel to complete booking. Everything is done in two taps. On the hotel side, hotels will be able to handle their inventory and minimize vacancy with greater lead times than traditional last-minute services. The hospitality industry is aflutter with new technology, with smaller players coming in to streamline back-end operations, and bigger guys launching interesting tech initiatives to keep competitive. For example, Starwood launched a robotic butler, while Hilton Hotels has a new app that allows you to choose your room and check out without speaking to another human. Roomlia launches today on the App Store with access to over 250 hotels and growing.</Content></Article>