<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Satirical Twitter Account @NBCDelayed Is The Best Part Of NBC’s Olympics Coverage</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/01/satirical-twitter-account-nbc-delayed-is-the-best-part-of-nbcs-olympics-coverage/</Url><Content>If you’ve grown sick of these NBC/Olympics stories, too bad! We have nearly two weeks of Olympics and their respective tape delays left. I don’t even want to count how many hours of delayed Ryan Seacrest that is. Here is a wild, EXCLUSIVE, Olympic story that could only be found by top-notch journalists with Internet connections and Twitter accounts (where could we find people with those qualifications? Not in New Orleans). Anyway, buried lede: A Twitter account, @NBCDelayed has been mocking NBC’s ill-conceived, tape-delayed coverage of the 2012 Olympic Games. The account has only posted 29 tweets, but they are comedic gold; starting two days after the opening ceremonies, it has attracted over 26,000 followers in under four days. Here are some of my favorites: BREAKING: American colonists announce independence, King to respond. — NBC Delayed (@NBCDelayed) July 29, 2012 Michael Jordan and Dream Team win gold medal in 117–85 victory against Croatia — NBC Delayed (@NBCDelayed) July 29, 2012 Tune in tonight for the Olympic Opening Ceremonies in Beijing #NBCFail — NBC Delayed (@NBCDelayed) July 29, 2012 BREAKING: Dewey defeats Truman in landslide. — NBC Delayed (@NBCDelayed) July 30, 2012 CORRECTION: Dewey doesn’t defeat Truman, Truman re-elected President. — NBC Delayed (@NBCDelayed) July 30, 2012 BREAKING: Roman Emperor Theodosius bans Olympic Games, NBC delay to catch up shortly. #394AD — NBC Delayed (@NBCDelayed) July 30, 2012 BREAKING: Underdog Jamaican bobsleigh team loses control and crashes. — NBC Delayed (@NBCDelayed) August 1, 2012 Want more Olympics? Don’t worry, we are now running a delayed version of our delayed broadcast. — NBC Delayed (@NBCDelayed) August 1, 2012 I don’t know about you, but I can’t wait until Twitter tips off NBC, NBC files a complaint and Twitter suspends the account before re-activating it and apologizing. Man, wouldn’t that be a crazy sequence of events?</Content></Article>