<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Sequoia Capital’s Jim Goetz Will Be With Us At Disrupt SF</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/29/sequoia-capitals-jim-goetz-will-be-with-us-at-disrupt-sf/</Url><Content>Sequoia Capital partner Jim Goetz, who focuses on mobile, software and enterprise investments for the firm, has had a busy year. Jive and Palo Alto Networks, companies where Goetz serves on the board of directors, have both gone public successfully. Sequoia was also in mobile app du jour Instagram right before it sold to Facebook. And the firm has raised nearly $1 billion for new funds for its U.S., China and Israeli investments. Goetz will be onstage talking about his enterprise investments, the current IPO market and more. And he will be joining many other illustrious speaker at Disrupt including TechCrunch founder Michael Arrington, Twitter and Square’s Jack Dorsey, Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer, Salesforce CEO and Chairman Marc Benioff, super angel Ron Conway, Vinod Khosla, LinkedIn and Greylock Partners’ Reid Hoffman, San Francisco Mayor Ed Lee, John Borthwick, Cloudera’s Kirk Dunn, Emmy award-winning director Greg Yaitanes, Ben Horowitz, Twitter’s Biz Stone and Evan Williams, Path’s Dave Morin, Kevin Rose, Box’s Aaron Levie, Khan Academy’s Sal Khan, The Honest Company’s Jessica Alba and Brian Lee, and many more. Whew! You can view the whole list of speakers here. Get your tickets here while you still can! As always, if you are interested in becoming a sponsor, opportunities can be found here. Students can also come and be a part of Disrupt SF, for $300 here. Jim Goetz Partner, Sequoia Capital Jim Goetz is a Partner at Sequoia Capital and is inspired by founders who aim to disrupt the enterprise (Jive Software, Nimble Storage, Palo Alto Networks), or change the mobile landscape (AdMob, Sencha, WhatsApp). He was raised in the Midwest, studied as an engineer, gave up on a PhD to start his career as a rookie product manager at SynOptics (SNPX), and matured into a VP/GM before co-founding VitalSigns (ALU). Both as an entrepreneur and as an investor, Jim is most enthused when teaming with others to turn an authentic idea into a market leading technology company. Jim joined Sequoia Capital in 2004, and has also led Sequoia’s Investments in Appirio, Barracuda Networks, Clearwell (SYMC), Drawbridge, eMeter (SI), Flite, Metaswitch, Pocket Gems, and Ruckus. Prior to joining Sequoia, Jim served as a General Partner at Accel Partners where he led the investments in BroadJump (MOTV), Entrisphere (ERIC), Peribit (JNPR), RGB, Rhapsody (BRCD), Timetra (ALA) and Topspin (CSCO). Prior to VitalSigns and Synoptics, Jim held various product and marketing positions at AT&amp;T, AT&amp;T Bell Labs, and Digital Equipment. Jim has a BS in Electrical and Computer Engineering from the University of Cincinnati and an MS in Electrical Engineering from Stanford University. Sept. 8th - 12th in San Francisco Event Guide What is Disrupt? Early Bird Ticket Sales Startup Battlefield Hackathon Startup Alley Sponsor Info</Content></Article>