<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Tesla’s Newest Car Is AWD And Goes 0-60 In 3 2 Seconds</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/10/09/teslas-new-p85d-is-awd-and-goes-0-60-in-3-2-seconds/</Url><Content>Whoops! While people are still filing their way into the building where Elon Musk will “unveil the D”, it looks like word just trickled out a bit early by way of a broken news embargo. We’re at the event and will report back on the news as it breaks, but here’s what we know so far. As we pieced together last week, the “D” stands for “Dual Motor” — or all-wheel drive. There will be three new models, all based on the company’s Model S: the 60D, 85D, and highest-end P85D. The 60D and 85D are tuned for distance, while the P85D is turned for performance. The 60D will have a 60 kWh battery that gets a range of 225 miles at 65 miles per hour. The 85D and P85D will both have 85 kWh batteries; the 85D will get 295 miles per charge, while the P85D gets 275 miles per charge. Update: Looks like the base prices for the 60D, 85D, and P85D will be $89,570, $97,570, and $120,170 respectively. And by performance, we mean crazy performance. The P85D is said to go from 0 to 60 in 3.2 seconds. That makes it one of the fastest sedans in the world The cars won’t be self-driving, but they will be the first to introduce autonomous functionality to Tesla’s lineup. The new models will be able to read speed limit signs, warn the driver when they’re drifting from their lane, automatically brake when you’re barreling toward someone’s rear end, and automatically change lanes when the driver users their turn signal. Update: It’ll self park. You can get out of your car in your driveway, and it’ll park itself in your garage. On the new autonomy features, Elon Musk mentioned that the sensors can “see a small child, or even a dog” — even at 150mph. Because they require a new sensor array, the new autonomy features are not compatible with older Model S. The highest end model, the P85D, is said to start shipping in December; the 60D/85D, meanwhile, will go out in February of next year.</Content></Article>