<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>The Media Nuke That Is TechCrunch Disrupt</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/10/27/the-media-nuke-that-is-techcrunch-disrupt/</Url><Content>I told you so. For the last few months in the run-up to TechCrunch Disrupt in London last week, I’d been telling everyone I knew in Europe that what we were bringing would be a different type of event to this global city. The first aspect of this was that, unlike 99% of conferences out there, no-one appearing on stage at Disrupt remains unchallenged about what they say. We rack up our journalists in front of every speaker and we hold their feet to the fire. And as you can see from the coverage, there was quite a few incidences of rather warm feet by the end of it. But that also means speakers step up to the plate and give their all in explaining how their companies are faring. Normally good speakers are made great because of this. The second aspect of Disrupt is the sheer amount of media that attends. We see that particularly in San Francisco. But London, being a centre for global media (what credible media outlet does NOT have an office in London?), helped us amass the greatest number of journalists to cover Disrupt than we have ever seen outside Silicon Valley. Not only was the tech press there, but also the mainstream media, from TV channels to online to print. What is the upshot of these vanity metrics? Well, bluntly, enormous amounts of coverage for the startups that appear both on stage, in the Alley, and even those just wandering around as delegates. That’s the magic of Disrupt, and it can’t be taken lightly. If startups are about one thing — other than becoming big global success stories of course — it’s about getting attention. The first day for Disrupt London saw around 100 media outlets attending, including The Financial Times, City AM, The Independent, Business Insider and CNBC. Some highlights included Tim Armstrong speaking live with Bloomberg live as well as CNBC and BBC World Business Report, the BBC World New’s flagship business programme. CNBC were at the event throughout the day, covering the event across three shows: Squawk, World Exchange and European Closing Bell. The BBC’s flagship current affairs programme, Newsnight, was also there for the whole day filming a piece which eventually appeared online. They focused on the Battlefield. BBC Radio 4 and the BBC World Service for Spanish-speaking countries was also there, focusing on Startup Alley. The second day of TechCrunch Disrupt in London went extremely well, with top tier media attending including The New York Times, CNN, The Daily Telegraph, The Times and The Evening Standard. In particular, City AM, the free daily newspaper for the business and financial heart of London with a circulation over 108,000 in print alone, gave us particular support with news from Disrupt appearing on the front pages several times. We also had a strong broadcast presence with APTN; Reuters TV who also spoke with start-ups; CNBC were down again and spoke with startups and TechCrunch staff. Social media around Disrupt also ran into the thousands of Tweets and millions of impressions via social. Disrupt is a Media Nuke, so just remember that when you are deciding whether to attend next year… Picture courtesy of Heisenberg Media MEDIA COVERAGE OF DISRUPT LONDON CNBC VIDEO: The BattleField Startup Alley Hackathon Justin Kan interview Tim Armstrong interview Transferwise interview City A.M. TechCrunch Disrupt in London: City’s rising tech talent is the star of the show Interview: Editor-at-large of Techcrunch Mike Butcher Techcrunch Disrupt: Let the (tech startup) battle commence Index expecting $10bn EU startup Techcrunch Disrupt: Mike Butcher and Morten Lund‘s make-up selfie London’s tech boom is more than just hype – and the City is at its heart TechCrunch Disrupt: Neelie Kroes dodges Jean-Claude Juncker question as AOL’s Tim Armstrong denies Yahoo merger Evening Standard It’s Crunch Time: All You Need to Know About TechCrunch Disrupt Google commits extra $25 million to European tech start-ups Financial Times Google Ventures spells out strategy for investing in Europe CNBC EU needs risk-takers to compete with US: EU’s Kroes Digital medicine? High-tech health care on the way Bloomberg AOL Considering Spinning Off Startup Database Unit CrunchBase Huffington Post Why News Apps Should Stop Biting the Hands That Feed Them The Independent Google commits extra $25m to Europe’s tech start ups Businessinsider.com Kids Need To Understand That Posting On The Internet Has Consequences, Says EU Digital Commissioner The Team Behind Google’s New $100 Million London VC Fund Are All In One Photo At Last The Story Of Video Games Streaming Site Twitch After Years Of Success, Mind Candy CEO Speaks Out About The Hellish Last 18 Months VentureBeat Tim Armstrong says AOL and Yahoo will not merge The Next Web Fab CEO: We were spending $14 million per month before Hem pivot Mind Candy CEO says Moshi Monsters popularity is dwindling on the Web, and revenue is ‘not good’ The Register EU digi tzar: ‘I like the nickname STEELIE NEELIE. Yeah, why not’ ITProPortal.com TechCrunch Disrupt Europe 2014: News, photos and the Startup Battlefield LIVE Nasdaq.com AOL’s Tim Armstrong Says He Isn’t Thinking About Yahoo At All – Presented by: The Aol. On Network Streetinsider.com AOL, Inc. (AOL) has No Plans to Merge with Yahoo! (YHOO) – CEO Armstrong SeattleSportsNut.com Hard to believe that Disrupt London opens tomorrow! As always,… TechCityNews.com Google Ventures Europe To Start Small With $125 Million Fund Crate dominates Battlefield to take £30,000 prize Wired.co.uk Twitch Co-Founder Attributes Startup Success to Resilience Waze Co-Founder. I’ll Fall in Love with The Problem Not The Solution TapTalk: we’re not worried about Facebook’s copycat App Neelie Kroes on ‘right to be forgotten’ and Europe’s digital future MarketWatch.com CloudCannon Lands $500K in funding in partnership with Rightside with Global at TechCrunch Disrupt Europe BBC TechCrunch in London: The battle to be noticed Bloomberg TV AOL CEO Armstrong: Lots of Innovations Left in Online Ads Reuters TV Finding Europe’s next tech titan CNBC Are these the next billion-dollar tech ‘unicorns’? Daily Mail Don’t tell the teacher! The app that uses your phone’s camera to solve any math equation it sees TIME This App Can Scan and Solve Math Equations Instantly Tech Times PhotoMath Can Solve Math Problems for you Mashable PhotoMath: Match Student’s New Best Friend is the Teacher’s Nightmare Digital Journal Math Teachers Beware: New app solves equations with camera Startups.co.uk Michael Acton Smith Speaks Out on Facing Tough Times on Mind Candy Winner of TechCrunch London Startup Battlefield revealed Dailydot.com Introducing PhotoMath, the app that helps you cheat on tests Business2communications.com PhotoMath Is An App That Takes Pictures Of Equations, Then Solves Them Stuff.tv Raspberry Pi will soon have its own display German media on the winner of Battlefield and other Disrupt news: futurezone vol zdnet chip mobilegeeks IT Times webmagazin winfuture Croatia: Netokracija</Content></Article>