<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>The Pirate Bay Launches A Mobile Website For Torrenting From Your Smartphone</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/25/the-pirate-bay-launches-a-mobile-website-for-torrenting-from-your-smartphone/</Url><Content>Everyone’s favorite torrent site has just rolled out a mobile version: The Pirate Bay has now launched a new, mobile-optimized website it’s calling The Mobile Bay. Designed to work better on smartphones and tablets, like those running the iOS or Android operating system, the new site has an updated layout that’s easier to read and navigate. News of the site’s debut was first reported by the blog Torrent Freak, which covers torrenting, piracy and file-sharing. The team behind The Pirate Bay admitted to the blog in an interview that “the normal version of the site renders like crap on mobile devices.” That is, when visitors loaded up the normal version of The Pirate Bay site on their smartphone, the site would just appear smaller. That actually made it harder to use. The new version, however, offers easy-to-tap buttons to search, browse as well as view recent torrents or the top 100. You can also search the site, filtering by media type (audio, video, games, etc.) Also like the desktop site, the mobile version of the website is filled with ads. On a mobile phone, they’re even more annoying – especially since you likely don’t have a mobile version of “ad block” or “flash block” to hide some of them from view. Instead, the ads will open up new web pages which take you away from The Mobile Bay and even direct you to the App Store automatically. On iOS, visitors won’t be able to actually download torrents from their mobile device if it’s not jailbroken, but the BlackBerry and Android app stores have a variety of torrenting clients to choose from. Torrent Freak also reported that The Mobile Bay is one of many new projects in the pipeline. Though it is one of the largest visible updates to The Pirate Bay in years, the team is now working on a few other things including dedicated websites for the TV, movie and music sections of The Pirate Bay, and something called “RSSbay,” which will offer personalized RSS feeds to enable people to launch torrents remotely. Image credit: Torrent Freak</Content></Article>