<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Twitch CEO Emmett Shear And COO Kevin Lin To Speak At Disrupt SF</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/25/twitch-ceo-emmett-shear-and-coo-kevin-lin-to-speak-at-disrupt-sf/</Url><Content>Twitch is coming to Disrupt SF in early September. The event, like everything Twitch does, will, of course, be streamed live. Twitch is a media monster. It’s at the forefront of the exploding eSports industry, as well as representing the entire video game ecosystem, including publishers, developers, media outlets and casual user generated gaming content. Just three years old, the video streaming service is changing the way gamers interact while providing multibillion avenues for advertisers. Google is reportedly looking into buying the company for north of a billion dollars. We’re excited to have Twitch co-founder and CEO Emmett Shear and COO Kevin Lin join us on stage at Disrupt SF where we may or may not spend the time collectively playing through all of the Pokémon games live. Twitch was born out of Justin.TV in 2011. Since its founding, Twitch has stuck to its mission of providing a unique experience for gamers. Using a gaming system or computer, users can broadcast or watch gameplay sessions. It’s become immensely popular. Stats about Twitch are mind boggling: The company brags that 50 million people use the service monthly, consuming more than 13 billion minutes of video. The company doubled its audience in 2013. League of Legends is the biggest draw with 27 million daily players as of January. During peak times, the Wall Street Journal stated that Twitch can be the fourth-largest consumer of Internet traffic, trailing behind just Netflix, Google and Apple. In short, gamers love watching other gamers play. Twitch’s Shear and Lin join other notable founders and entrepreneurs speaking at Disrupt including Salesforce’s Marc Benioff, Product Hunt’s Ryan Hoover and Tinder’s Sean Rad. Disrupt SF tickets are still available at an early bird discount. The event takes place in at San Francisco’s Pier 48 September 8 – 10. TC Cribs Tours Twitch, Where Playing Games Is Part Of The Job Facebook LinkedIn Twitch’s Otherworldly Office | TC Cribs</Content></Article>