<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Twitch Partners With Gameloft To Stream Live From Mobile Games  Starting With Asphalt 8</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/17/twitch-gameloft-asphalt-8/</Url><Content>Video game streaming startup Twitch has spent the last few years building tools that will let developers build live streaming into their games on multiple platforms. After reaching the major gaming consoles, it’s now ready to go mobile, by partnering with developer Gameloft to enable live streaming gameplay from popular racing game Asphalt 8. Twitch started out by enabling gamers to broadcast matches from their PCs, but over time has worked its way into the console gaming market. With the latest update to their gaming platforms, Twitch is now integrated with Sony’s PlayStation 4 and Microsoft Xbox One. Clearly mobile was the next big step for Twitch. To make its way into a new generation powerful new mobile games, it’s partnered with game developer Gameloft, producer of its own titles such as Asphalt, Order &amp; Chaos, Modern Combat, and Dungeon Hunter, along with a wide range of licensed games such as Thor: The Dark World and Despicable Me: Minion Rush. The first mobile title to include live Twitch streaming is Gameloft’s Asphalt 8: Airborne, which will have the functionality added as part of an update to the app. Streaming will be optimized for the newest generation of iOS products running Apple’s A7 chip, meaning the iPhone 5S, iPad Air, and iPad Mini. For Twitch, the integration will introduce a huge mobile streaming to a large new audience, as the game has already been downloaded 48 million times. But it will also introduce new features to mobile gamers. In addition to live streaming of the game, the integration will give gamers the ability to stream their voice and image using the device’s front-facing camera. Players can also archive streams and share them on the web, or view streams from others directly within the app.</Content></Article>