<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Watch The 2011 Web 2 0 Summit Day Two Live</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2011/10/18/watch-the-2011-web-2-0-summit-day-two-live/</Url><Content>We’re at the Palace Hotel for day two of for the 2011 Web 2.0 Summit, where the lineup for the next three days consists of almost everyone on the entire Internet. The. entire. Internet. In case you didn’t get to be a part of the in-person action, you and your friends at home can follow along from the Livestream above, starting at 1130 a.m. PST. Today’s speaker highlights include the Founder and CEO of Dell, Michael Dell, Foursquare Co-founder Dennis Crowley, Andreessen Horowitz General Partner, Ben Horowitz, and Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer. It’s a star-studded lineup and should be a very exciting and fast-paced day. Full Schedule Below: 10:30am Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Opening Remarks John Battelle (Federated Media Publishing Inc.), Edwin M. Lee (City &amp; County of San Francisco) 10:35am Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Michael Dell, Chairman &amp; CEO, Dell Inc. Michael Dell (Dell Inc.), John Battelle (Federated Media Publishing Inc.) 11:00am Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Pivot Bill Gross (Idealab, Ubermedia) 11:05am Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Pivot Aileen Lee (Kleiner Perkins Caufield &amp; Byers) 11:10am Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom High Order Bit Danny Weitzner (White House Office of Science and Technology Policy) 11:20am Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Dr. Ann Cavoukian, Information and Privacy Commissioner of Ontario, Canada &amp; David Vladeck, FTC Bureau 11:50am Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Dennis Crowley, Co-founder, foursquare Dennis Crowley (foursquare), John Heilemann (New York Magazine) 12:05pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Ben Horowitz, General Partner, Andreessen Horowitz Ben Horowitz (Andreessen Horowitz), John Heilemann (New York Magazine) 2:00pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom High Order Bit Andrew Stalbow (Rovio Entertainment Ltd.) 2:15pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom John Partridge, President, Visa Inc. &amp; Dan Schulman, Group President for Enterprise Growth, American Express John Partridge (Visa Inc.), Dan Schulman (American Express Company), John Battelle (Federated Media Publishing Inc.) 2:40pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Internet Trends Mary Meeker (Kleiner Perkins Caufield &amp; Byers) 3:05pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom The ‘Dark Side’ of Data: The NSA ThinThread Tale Thomas Drake (Knowpari Systems, LLC) 3:20pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Introducing X.Commerce Matthew Mengerink (eBay), Tim O’Reilly (O’Reilly Media, Inc.) 4:00pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Quantifying Entrepreneurship Bill Maris (Google Ventures), Graham Spencer (Google Ventures) 4:10pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Jack Tretton, President &amp; CEO, Sony Computer Entertainment of America Jack Tretton ( Sony Computer Entertainment of America (SCEA)), Jane McGonigal (Social Chocolate) 4:30pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Pivot Alyssa Henry (Amazon Web Services) 4:35pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom High Order Bit Ken Goldberg (UC Berkeley and Hybrid Wisdom Labs) 4:45pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom High Order Bit Gil Elbaz (Factual) 4:55pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Tim Westergren, Founder &amp; Chief Strategy Officer, Pandora Tim Westergren (Pandora), Adam Lashinsky (Fortune Magazine) 5:15pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Michael Roth, Chairman &amp; CEO, Interpublic Group of Companies Michael Roth (Interpublic), John Battelle (Federated Media Publishing Inc.) 5:35pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Steve Ballmer, CEO, Microsoft Corporation Steve Ballmer (Microsoft Corporation), John Battelle (Federated Media Publishing Inc.) 5:55pm Plenary Room: Grand Ballroom Closing Remarks</Content></Article>