<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Xamarin Raises $16M Series B Round Led By Lead Edge Capital  Passes 20 000 Paid Developer Seats</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2013/07/17/xamarin-raises-16m-series-b-round-led-by-lead-edge-capital-passes-20000-paid-developer-seats/</Url><Content>Xamarin, the cross-platform development platform for native apps for iOS, Android, OS X and Windows, today announced that it has closed an opportunistic $16 million Series B round led by Lead Edge Capital. The company’s Series A investors Charles River Ventures, Ignition Partners and Floodgate also participated in this round. In total, including the $12 million Series A round, Xamarin has now raised $28 million. The company, which focuses strongly on making mobile app development easier for enterprises, also today announced that its developer community has now grown to over 350,000 members and includes 20,000 paid developer seats. The company is clearly on a roll right now. Earlier this year, Xamarin hosted its first developer conference, which quickly sold out, and launched a number of innovative products, including it’s new mobile UI testing platform. As Xamarin’s CEO Nat Friedman told me, the company plans to use the funding to increase investment in its developer platform, “particularly in pre-built component and apps to help developers build great apps faster,” and its Test Cloud. Xamarin also plans to double its sales team by the end of this year. “In the very near future, every business process and customer interaction will happen on a mobile device,” Friedman, said in a statement today. “Xamarin’s unique approach of enabling businesses to rapidly deliver fully native apps for multiple device platforms has resulted in incredible revenue growth and market momentum. This success, combined with this opportunistic Series B round, provides the foundation for exponential future growth for the company.” He also told me that the company was approached by investors, but the driving motivation behind closing this round was “to position Xamarin to dominate the mobile development market.” The company, he argues, is growing significantly faster that its competitors and “augmenting that success with an additional round pours more fuel on the fire.”</Content></Article>