<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>Yahoo Releases Aviate Homescreen For Android To Organize Your Life</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/23/yahoo-releases-aviate-homescreen-for-android-to-organize-your-life/</Url><Content>Yahoo has today launched a new smartphone UI experience called Aviate, which is available for Android phones (English speaking only). The idea is that the company can dip their toes in the mobile OS waters without going all-in on anything, as Yahoo works to strengthen its mobile portfolio. Here’s what the official release has to say: Yahoo Aviate simplifies everything about your phone. It starts with a clean, new layout and apps automatically organized for you. But it’s not just about making your phone simpler – Aviate also makes your phone smarter by offering intelligent information throughout your day. Whether you’re on the go, at work, at a restaurant or just relaxing at home, Aviate automatically shows you apps and information that are useful to you based on what you’re up to. What type of information is that, you might ask? Essentially, it’s going for a Google Now type experience that is baked right into the UI. So, for example, Aviate users will get information around the weather in the morning so they dress smart. But it goes deeper than that. Aviate can integrate with your email and calendar information to give you single-click access to a conference call, or help you get to work on time based on random traffic changes. There’s also a twice-daily news summary baked into your homescreen, and Yahoo Aviate will automatically list your most popular contacts into a Favorites section. In other words, those who don’t enjoy the tedious process of tailoring your smartphone to all your own unique needs can potentially enjoy Yahoo’s automated version of that. Yahoo has made a big push in mobile of late, revamping old apps and releasing new ones to ensure the company doesn’t fall behind as the mobile ecosystem grows. This is yet another step in that direction, and as I said, one that tests the waters cautiously. Part of that effort includes an active M&amp;A lifestyle for the company, and Aviate was but one of many big purchases for the company. Aviate was acquired in January for a reported $80 million. If you want to download Aviate for your Android phone, check it out here. Collections - Framed Homescreen - Framed Location - Framed People - Framed Today - Morning - Framed  View Slideshow Previous Next Exit</Content></Article>