<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>YellowSchedule Raises €600K So That You Never Miss A Therapist Appointment Again</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/01/yellowschedule/</Url><Content>Dublin and Limerick-based YellowSchedule, which offers an online service to help therapists and clinics manage appointments and client records, has raised €600,000 from various angel investors, along with the taxpayer-funded Enterprise Ireland. Specifically, the angel investors participating are Sean Riddell and Jennifer Riddell, former CEO and former Head of Marketing of leading healthcare IT company EMIS — so a pretty decent fit for the young YellowSchedule. Competing with legacy therapy scheduling and CRM companies, whose offerings are often clunky and designed to work in older browsers without the usability that modern web standards provide, YellowSchedule enables therapists and other related industries to manage customer scheduling, records and relationships, as well as providing business analytics. It also counts more generic services, such as Schedulicity, Genbook and BookFresh, as competitors. In particular, after brother and sister duo Martina and Michael Skelly spotted a need for better appointment reminders, YellowSchedule aims to cut down on the number of missed therapy and related appointments, therefore increasing ROI for therapy providers. A no-show is potentially lost revenue, and this can often come down to simple forgetfulness. It can also be an early signal that a patient needs more support. To tackle this, the service provides automatic appointment prompts via email and SMS, with various paid tiers providing a set number of SMS messages, starting from £16.95 for 100 reminders. In addition to appointment reminders, another aspect of YellowSchedule is it enables self-booking for patients through its website, and in future mobile app, which also helps to increase attendance. “Reducing no-shows for our customers is more than just a revenue exercise,” explains CEO Martina Skelly. “Ensuring that patients adhere to treatment programmes leads to better patient outcomes and our 2 way messaging and indication of attendance can be an easy way to spot if a vulnerable patient is not feeling well.” Skelly says YellowSchedule’s customers also require additional privacy features, such as HIPAA compliance and data encryption. Today’s injection of capital will enable YellowSchedule to expand its marketing, with the aim to accelerate traction. It also plans to grow the team. Of note, Skelly tells me customers currently span 38 countries, however the startup’s mainly been targeting the U.S. and UK markets with over 70% of customers based in the U.S.</Content></Article>