<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>ZZ Photo Is A Photo App That Can Organize Your Snapshots By Pet</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2014/12/18/zz-photo-is-a-photo-app-that-can-organize-your-snapshots-by-pet/</Url><Content>Does your photo management solution recognize your cat? Your mom? Your dog? No, it does not. That’s why there’s ZZ Photo. The app, built by a Ukrainian team, is essentially a shoebox for all of your photos but with a few smarts built in. It is Windows-only right now but the team is working on mobile and Mac versions of the app. The app won our weekly TC Radio Pitch-Off thanks to their brand manager Tatiana Vezhis’ vibrant description of the tool. The founders, Alexander Lisovskiy and Artem Chernodub have experience in computer vision and desktop programming. Chernodub is actually head of the computer vision department at the MMSP of National Academy of Science of Ukraine. They’ve seen a few hundred users so far – they just launched – but they haven’t spent much on coding and the app is ready to download. It essentially allows you to organize your photos by subject and it can automatically recognize people (and the aforementioned pets) and store your photos for easy viewing. “The market we are entering is not crowded with competitors. In fact, most of them solve only one problem – photo viewing, while ZZ Photo is full-scale solution for collecting and organizing images at home photo libraries,” said Vezhis. “ZZ Photo is unique because it handles duplicate detection, similar pictures detection, recognizing faces, and detecting pets.” The app will soon have cloud access as well. “The idea of launching this product came to our CEO when he was nervously looking for his newborn son’s photo at his computer and he almost had a heart attack when he thought he’d lost them forever,” said Vezhis. “ZZ Photo can detect pets. We can detect your cat, its fluffy girlfriend next door or your mother’s favorite kitty as well as all dogs in your family during their lifetime.” The app costs $29 and is available now.</Content></Article>