<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><Article><Title>“Human Error” Caused Vine’s DildoPlay Editor’s Pick</Title><Url>http://techcrunch.com/2013/01/28/human-error-caused-vines-dildoplay-editors-pick/</Url><Content>This morning, new Vine users woke up to quite the treat. Twitter’s new video sharing app launched a NSFW, porn clip called “DildoPlay” to the top of the Editor’s Picks section of the app, a place where users can browse the latest and greatest vines. Vine only launched last week, and has already been reported as having a small porn problem. Searching the hashtag #porn within the app will give you a peek at what I’m talking about. This is expected from almost any new visually focused social network. If you build it, sex will come. However, to have a hardcore porn clip at the top of the app’s Editor’s Picks section takes us past “Whoops!” and into full-fledged “Holy Shit” land. According to Twitter, the mistake was caused by human error. Here’s the full statement from a spokesperson: A human error resulted in a video with adult content becoming one of the videos in Editor’s Picks, and upon realizing this mistake we removed the video immediately. We apologize to our users for the error. Chances are, this isn’t the last we’ll hear about porn on Vine or this particular incident. A simple apology doesn’t really cover it, and claiming human error doesn’t really resolve the situation either. How is it possible that a Twitter or Vine employee went through the whole process of making this video an “Editor’s Pick” without realizing it was some serious pornography? We’re waiting for a more legitimate response to this incident and the porn issue on Vine, but until then, rest assured that this particular DildoPlay video won’t show up in your Explore section. (Unless you go looking for it.) The second question is what Apple is going to do. The app removed 500px app from the App Store last week claiming it was too easy to search for nude photos. What will Apple do this time, with a partner company no less? [via Gizmodo]</Content></Article>